(birds singing,
dog barking in distance)
Hey, Adam, remember me?
- Going to school, huh?
- Yeah.
Come on, I'll
give you a ride.
It's okay. It's on my way.
What are those for?
They're for your parents.
Get in, I'll explain.
You're not dressed.
You said you'd go
jogging with me
this morning.
Doesn't sound like me.
Have you been up all night?
I started digging through one
of the files I keep
on open serial murders
after you'd gone to bed,
and I lost track of time.
Still losing track of it,
as a matter of fact,
so, no jogging. Sorry.
I thought we both agreed
that a little exercise would
be a good addition
to your sobriety regimen.
For future reference, when I say
that I agree with you,
it means I'm not listening.
You know what else is great?
Jazzercise.
I'll get you some
leg warmers, a headband.
You'll look awesome.
I agree with you.
The Balloon Man?
Is that who you've
been researching?
Yeah. Came to my attention
while I was still
living in London.
New York's
very own bogeyman.
- Obviously, you've heard of him.
- Yeah.
He took his first victim
from Cobble Hill
about seven years ago.
I was living just
a few blocks away. Adam.
Adam something.
I think he's taken
six kids since then?
- Seven as of last night.
- What?
I heard it on my police
scanner app around midnight.
Ten-year-old Mariana Castillo
snatched from her bedroom
in Astoria, Queens,
the abductor's signature
batch of balloons
left fluttering behind.
I'd like to think that
Fleet Street would have devised
a more inventive sobriquet
than "The Balloon Man,"
but I do enjoy the inadvertent
E.E. Cummings reference.
Well, if you only heard it
on the scanner, then you haven't
actually been assigned
to the case.
Yet.
Child abductions
and serial murders mean
psychiatric consultants
and joint task forces,
which in turn means
that Gregson can't call me in
until the police
commissioner approves.
And he doesn't get in
until 8:30 a.m.
Sharp. Add approximately
three minutes for coffee,
another six for a trip
to the loo.
Should be calling me in about,
hmm, 15 minutes.
(phone ringing)
Or sooner.
Holmes.
Crescent Street, Astoria.
I'll be there presently.
I could have sworn I was wearing
a shirt at some point.
GREGSON:
The girl's bedroom
is in the back.
Perp forced the lock on her
window around 9:30 last night,
took her, tied the
balloons to her bed.
Mom's a painter.
She went to a friend's gallery.
Dad went to the
bodega on the corner
to get some wine
around 9:45.
That's freshly broken.
By the girl, presumably,
grabbing for a handhold.
That's good.
She's a fighter.
If little girls could
actually win fights
against grown men, then, yeah,
it would be a cause
for great optimism.
(indistinct chatter)
What's this?
Parents are making a plea
to the twist that took their kid.
They mustn't.
Why not?
Excuse me. You can't do this.
We're live in ten, buddy,
so if you wouldn't mind.
You don't understand. It's...
We're on in ten, nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four, three...
Look, I'm sorry.
Two, one.
Hey. Sherlock!
I'm sorry. I warned him!
MAN: What is this?
Who are you?
I'm just the man who's trying
to keep these people from
killing your daughter.
Mr. Holmes is a consultant with
the department, Mr. Castillo.
Daniel Peters, Kayla Jackson,
Billy Crawford.
Victims two, three and
five of the Balloon Man.
The only ones whose
bodies were found.
Forensics estimated
he kept Daniel alive
for a full day before burial,
Kayla for half a day,
Billy for almost two days.
Why the discrepancy?
Sherlock, they lost their
daughter. I think...
Last night, I discovered
a direct correlation
between the quickness
with which the killer
dispatched his victims
and the extent of their
parents' media exposure.
I could show you
the spreadsheet,
but in sum--
the more interviews,
the faster
the children died.
Is he right?
Usually.
I don't understand.
What does it matter
how many interviews we do?
The Balloon Man feeds off
the public grief
of his victims' families.
You nourish him,
he'll get bored, end the game.
Keep him hungry,
we might have two days.
You want to get
your little girl back?
It's simple.
You do everything I say.
♪ Elementary 1x03 ♪
Child Predator
Original Air Date on October 18, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
WATSON:
Kemper.
Hmm?
That was the name
of the Balloon Man's
first victim.
Adam Kemper.
I just remembered.
The police found those
balloons on the sidewalk
where he'd taken Adam, the
ones that said, "Thank you"
Like Adam's parents had given
him some sort of gift.
I read all the articles
over the years.
I know it destroys
the victims' families,
but being here in
person is just...
Perhaps you'd like
to go outside.
I'm fine, thanks. I just...
No, it's not an expression
of concern. It's a request.
You're distracting me.
I'm distracting you.
Because clearly,
this is all about you.
Excuse me!
No, no, no, no, it's okay.
BELL:
Mr. Castillo, you can't
blame yourself
for what happened.
Actually, he can.
Excuse me?
Not for your daughter's
abduction, of course.
The kidnapper would have found
a way to take her eventually.
But you can and
should blame yourself
for impeding our
investigation.
I told you everything.
If everything includes
one very big lie.
Where's the wine that you
claimed you were buying
when your daughter
was taken last night?
In your hand.
And there's the lie.
Bodegas put the price tag
on the cap itself.
It saves stacking time.
Tag-- bottom.
You-- liar.
Obviously, you bought this
at another time,
presumably from the liquor store
on Atlantic where
you purchased
the case of Prosecco
you have in your pantry.
The bottle was
already in your fridge,
so it provided
an effective cover
as to why you were really
out of the house.
Tell us her name, Mr. Castillo,
right now.
Whose name?
His mistress.
(laughs)
There's no point
in trying to deny it.
Your lemon press gave you away.
Well, presses, to be precise.
One old.
One quite new,
less than a year. The pattern
repeats itself with
your two corkscrews,
the pepper mills.
The older items
belong to you and your wife.
The doubles were bought
by you when you moved
into your own place on Long Island.
How...?
I found a letter in your
mail forwarded to you
from a long-term stay
hotel chain in Islip.
I assume that you
and your wife separated
for a while,
and then reconciled?
Which brings me
to your Caller ID.
You took a 15-second call
from a Long Island area code
last night right before
you stepped out of the house.
Presumably, from the woman who
precipitated your separation.
She rang, you walked
out of the house.
Why else would you hide
information from the police
when you're clearly desperate
to get your daughter back?
When Sara and I were separated,
I dated a co-worker.
She called me last night, said
she was in the neighborhood
and needed to see
me, but I swear,
I only went out to
tell her the she had
to stay away for good.
How could you not say anything?
Where did you meet her?
On the street, a few houses
down from here, but I swear,
I didn't go into her car.
I just talked to her
through her window.
I'd like to speak with her.
She had nothing to do with this.
Probably not, but can you think
of anyone else who was parked
on your block last night?
'Cause if she was
waiting for you,
I assume she was
facing your house.
If she was facing
your house...
Maybe she saw
something that
could help us find the guy
who took your daughter.
I'm sorry. (sniffles)
I just... I can't believe
I'm the reason
that lunatic got his hands
on Roberto's daughter.
If I hadn't called him, then...
GREGSON: Now, Ms.-Ms. Thomas,
it's all right.
Did you see or hear anything
out of the ordinary?
I never got out of my car.
So, what now?
THOMAS: I was just looking
at Roberto...
Do we go back to the Castillo
house, talk to the parents more?
You're doing it again--
talking.
What? I'm not
supposed to talk?
Situations like these,
cases that require
my total concentration--
I talk to you,
never the other way around.
What in the hell...?
Shh, shh.
THOMAS: ...and I headed
for the corner,
and then, um, some other car ran
the stop sign, almost hit me.
This was approximately when?
Never mind.
I already know. 9:40.
The vine that the girl managed
to pull free from the side
of the house-- it means
she was awake and struggling
when Balloon Man took her.
So?
So, examinations of
the three victims whose bodies
were recovered indicated
that he chloroformed them.
He got sloppy with Mariana
Castillo, rushed things.
Why? Because of the sirens.
What sirens?
Listening to my scanner
last night,
I heard a report that preceded
Roberto Castillo's call
to 911 by mere minutes.
Some sort of domestic dispute.
A squad car was dispatched
to an address less than two
blocks from the Castillo home,
sirens blaring.
You think the perp panicked, and
thought the sirens were for him.
So he grabbed
the girl and ran.
Stashed her in his car, and
then tore through the stop sign.
Right in front
of Ms. Thomas here.
BELL:
The car that almost hit you--
do you remember
what it looked like?
Um, actually,
it was a van.
It's a kidnapper's vehicle of
choice. What else? Make? Model?
It happened so fast.
Uh, I'm not really a car person.
Are you a color person? I'll get
you started. Red? Blue? Black?
Brown. Dark brown.
So, what are we
looking for?
Home security camera?
Neighbor
with a photographic memory?
Hey, care to explain what
you said back at the station
about, you know, you talking
to me, not the other way around?
Yes, well aware
I'm doing it again.
I've found, over the years,
that nothing clears up
a difficult case
so much as stating it
to another person.
I talk, they listen,
and in talking,
I make connections
I may have otherwise missed.
One-way street, not two.
Who did you speak
to back in London?
Oh, lots of people.
Waitstaff, cabdrivers.
The occasional prostitute.
Better listeners
than you might think.
Right. You don't look good.
My appearance has always meant
so much to me.
You haven't eaten today, have you?
(sighs)
No sleep,
no food...
Will make Sherlock
a dull boy.
People in recovery
have a tendency to relapse
when they
haven't eaten...
You know what, Watson?
I take it all back.
I'm beginning
to find the chatter
that accompanies
your companionship
extremely useful.
A bit like white noise.
It puts me in a state where
I think, and I observe better.
For example...
What? If this is your idea
of a brown van,
then you're even more
sleep-deprived than I thought.
Note the parking tickets. Hmm?
It's been here for days.
Yet there are small
skid marks beneath each tire,
indicating it's been moved
several inches.
Someone sideswiped it.
My money is
on a speeding van
driven
by a panicked kidnapper.
Well, the paint from the
other car is supposed to be...
It's dark brown as per
Ms. Thomas' description.
But there's blue
and white paint
mixed in with the brown.
Means it's brown now,
but was originally painted
white and blue--
a very distinctive white
and blue as a matter of fact.
Detective Bell.
Excuse me.
We are looking for a
decommissioned NYPD van,
presumably sold at auction,
then painted brown.
It has a long scrape
down one side
where it struck
this sedan.
Issue the BOLO now,
we may find the Balloon
Man before lunch.
I'm not sleeping.
I'm just reviewing the details
of the case in my mind.
I'm sorry, were
you talking to me?
'Cause I thought I was
just a cavernous expanse
between two ears.
You mustn't be
so sensitive, Watson.
The service you're providing
is quite valuable.
For a brief stretch
in London,
I talked only to a phrenology
bust I kept in my study.
I named him Angus.
Wasn't the same.
I realized that when
it came to listeners,
I preferred animate
to inanimate.
Was quite
a breakthrough, really.
Angus.
I'm glad I made it to
the animate category.
Just got a hit
on our BOLO.
Car Five, you
still got the eye?
CAR FIVE: Yeah, driver's a male white
wearing a hoodie.
All I can make out.
Aviation One, you getting anything
on the thermal imaging?
AVIATION ONE: Negative.
We're too high to see if...
CAR FIVE: He made us.
Heading north on 78th.
(sirens wailing)
Police!
Hands up!
(grunts)
She's not here.
(indistinct radio transmission)
(panting)
Cap, that's not our guy.
He would have been
in sixth grade
when Balloon Man took
his first victim.
GREGSON:
Hey, what are you doing?
Holmes.
Sorry,
it's just that,
well, according
to that birthmark on his neck,
you're quite right.
This is not the man that took
Adam Kemper back in 2005.
This is Adam Kemper.
BELL:
Adam.
Adam, please
talk to me.
Now, we know who you are, Adam,
your fingerprints confirmed it,
so come on,
tell me how you ended up
in that van.
We've got
a psychiatrist coming,
but I don't think it's going
to make much difference.
This kid just doesn't
want to engage.
WATSON:
Well, have you notified
his parents?
Commissioner
made the call.
They're on their way.
Should only take 'em
an hour
to fight through
all the media outside.
Story of the century, this.
Missing boy presumed dead,
recovered after all these years.
WATSON: Well, the fact that he was
found in a van that we thought
belonged to the
Balloon Man--
that's obviously more
than a coincidence, right?
I read about a
case like this.
Police in Dubuque
found a 15-year-old
who'd been missing
for seven years.
Now, the man who
had taken him
had enrolled
him in school.
He even let him have
friends over to the house.
The boy never tried to
leave because he had grown
to sympathize
with his captor.
If that's what's
happened here,
it would explain why Adam
was running from the police
instead of to them.
Because he's actually grown
to care for the lunatic.
If Adam's
still alive,
maybe some of the
other victims are, too.
Adam was special-- his first.
The Balloon Man's second
and third victims are
two of only three
to be recovered.
Their condition suggests that
he rather liked the killing.
After he had a taste, I don't
believe he ever looked back.
Question now is,
what role did Adam play
in their deaths?
WATSON:
You think Adam helped him?
Well, you said it yourself:
he sympathized with his captor.
Question is, to what degree?
We did find him
in that van.
CSU is processing it
for evidence
to try and prove whether
Mariana Castillo was inside.
In the meantime, we've got
Adam on auto theft,
but if he doesn't start
talking to us soon,
we're going to run
out of time to find
the Castillo girl.
I want to talk to him.
I think I can get
through to him.
Holmes, this is a
delicate situation.
And I can, on occasion, be
indelicate, I'm well aware,
but if you think
I'd do anything
to jeopardize the
life of that girl...
Intentionally,
of course not.
We're talking
about a kid here--
a kid that's been traumatized,
maybe even brainwashed.
A kid who wouldn't even be
here if it wasn't for me.
What, oh, you think that gives
you the right to question him?
You're a consultant,
not a cop.
And given
the very real possibility
that the young man
is accessory
to several horrific crimes,
maybe "not a cop"
is exactly what he needs
at the moment, hmm?
(elevator bell dings) Ten minutes--
that's all I ask.
You've got five.
(sighing)
Hello, Adam.
My name is Sherlock.
You can probably tell
from my accent,
I'm not a New York City
police officer,
nor am I
a psychiatrist,
which makes me the only person
you're going to talk to today
who isn't going
to lie to you.
The people
who were here earlier--
Detective Bell
and the others--
they told you that the man
who took you seven years ago
was a bad man,
that he hurt you, abused you.
But they don't know
the whole story, do they?
He also took care of you,
kept a roof over your head,
taught you to drive.
Loved you.
My father
packed me off
to boarding school when I was
just eight years old.
(chuckles)
I was a little bit
of a know-it-all--
well, I was
a massive know-it-all, actually.
Turned a lot of the other boys
at the school against me, hmm,
especially one
by the name of Anders Larson.
Now, over the course
of the next year,
Anders took his anger
out on me in, uh,
myriad cruel and terrible ways--
nothing close to what
you experienced, of course, but
it seemed worth mentioning.
You see...
the more Anders hurt me...
...the more I felt gratitude
that he was actually
paying attention to me.
That in, in tormenting me,
he was attempting
to correct what I knew
to be wrong with myself.
One day,
after a particularly brutal
lesson...
...left me in a very bad way,
a teacher asked me
who was responsible.
I said I'd fallen
down the stairs.
Funny, the things
that we do
for the people
that we care about.
Uh, did he do that to you--
the person that you care about?
No.
I was in my room
the other night...
and it was hot.
I tried to open the window,
but it was stuck,
and my hand went
through the pane.
(whispers
indistinctly)
And he took care of me.
He put a bandage on it.
Of course he did.
He loves you.
He does everything for me.
He comes home
every morning
and brings me doughnuts.
He doesn't need to, but he does.
I never even asked...
No more questions.
He lawyered up.
Via telepathy?
Via his parents.
They're here.
I'm sorry, I
know you have
questions for
Adam, but come on,
you think we don't know that
you think Adam may have had
something to do
with what happened
to the other
children?
It's a possibility, yes,
which is why we'd like
to keep talking to him--
to see if he can help us find
Mariana Castillo.
I can't imagine what they're
going through right now.
Hmm?
By the way, that was
really something
back there with Adam.
The story about your bully
was really very moving.
Any of it true?
I went
to boarding school.
ATTORNEY: You should know, Captain,
that we've already broached
the possibility
of an immunity deal
with the district attorney's
office.
Adam would be given immunity
for any crimes
he may have been compelled
to commit
by the individual who took him,
and in exchange he'd tell you
everything he knows about the man.
He'll also help you try and locate
the bodies of the victims
that were never recovered.
We expect to hear back
from the D.A. by morning.
By then it may be too late
for the Castillo girl.
ATTORNEY: Which is why we
very much hope
that you'll support
our proposal.
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
Yes?
Support the proposal,
don't support it.
It doesn't matter.
My conversation with Adam
may have been aborted,
but it was far
from a total waste.
What do you mean?
Adam said the Balloon Man
comes home every morning
with doughnuts.
That means he works nights.
It doesn't sound
like much, I know,
but it's more than we previously
knew about him.
And you think
you can run with that?
From a drop of water, a logician
can infer the possibility
of an Atlantic or a Niagara
without having seen
or heard of either one.
I've got my drop of water.
Now allow me to infer.
WATSON: He worked nights-- you
think that's really going
to be enough to identify
the Balloon Man?
Of course not,
but it's a start.
Our previous suspect pool
included
virtually every man in the city.
Now it's been reduced
to every man who works nights.
You're gonna stay up all
night again, aren't you?
You can't stop me,
Watson.
I don't care how I look,
I don't care how I smell,
I'm not going to sleep.
Well, I have no intention
of stopping you.
I mean, what you're doing
to your body isn't healthy,
you know, especially for
someone so fresh out of rehab,
but I get it.
I will happily loan you
my ears if it means
getting Mariana Castillo
back alive and well.
I appreciate that,
but at the moment
I do not require
a listener.
I will have nothing
to talk about
until I've reviewed
all of these files.
All right, then,
I'll take a box.
No, no, no, it doesn't
work like that.
My brain is the filter
all this needs to go
through, not yours.
I need to read every
word, study every image.
All right, then,
I'll help you stay awake.
All right, you know
where the coffee is.
It's not
about the coffee.
Whoa, then, what
are you proposing?
I'm gonna teach you
something--
a little trick that I learned
back in medical school.
(sighs)
(exhaling)
This is what they taught
you in medical school?
When I was cramming for a test
and I was tired,
I would do a hundred of these,
get my blood pumping.
Kept me from falling asleep.
I was valedictorian.
I'm just saying.
Watson!
He changed jobs.
Who?
The Balloon Man.
A few years ago, the
FBI worked a theory
that he was an
exterminator.
Adam Kemper's family had
had their house fumigated
just the week before
he disappeared.
Yes, I'm still
holding, yes.
No one thought
much of it
until these were taken
right outside the homes
of victims two and three.
Oh, both neighbors
had their houses tented.
In 2008, the FBI interviewed
all 35 of the employees
of the company that
fumigated the Kempers' home,
but failed to elicit
any strong suspects.
They eventually discarded their
theory when no connection
to extermination was found
in or around the homes
of the subsequent victims.
See, the thing is, I think
they were onto something.
I think the Balloon Man
was an exterminator,
but then changed jobs between
victims three and four.
See this?
It's a copy of The
Investor's Post.
You can tell from
the distinctive
salmon-colored
paper stock.
The parents of victim number
four had a subscription.
As do the parents
of Mariana Castillo,
the most recent victim.
I saw one in their
kitchen yesterday.
The parents of victims
five, six and seven
are not subscribers, but
have neighbors who are.
So the Balloon Man was an
exterminator; now he delivers
papers at night for
The Investor's Post.
Mm, he identified his first
three victims through
his first job, his last five
victims through his second.
I'm on the phone
with the paper now.
They're telling me the name
of the man responsible
for the Castillos' route.
They think I'm
a subscriber,
looking to send
a belated tip.
Yes, yes, hello.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
See any familiar names?
♪.
GREGSON:
Abbott's mother is listed
as the owner of the apartment,
but she died six months ago.
He put it as his home address
the last time
he renewed his driver's license.
Clear!
We got nothing, Captain.
The place is clean.
What's that?
GREGSON:
Smith, Smith,
head back to that room.
Copy that.
BELL:
"Congrats."
To who?
To us.
For finding his place.
GREGSON: Smith, what is that
on the balloon?
Bringing it to you, Captain.
You have something that's mine.
You have Adam.
You know who I am
and you know what I can do.
I've already killed six people.
If you haven't
released my son back to me
by noon tomorrow,
you can make it seven.
Please.
Make the trade.
Bring us back our daughter.
I'm afraid it's not that simple,
Mrs. Castillo.
The department can't trade
one victim for another.
Is that what you really
think Adam Kemper is?
I saw on the news
this morning,
the D.A. offered him
an immunity deal.
If he's just a victim, what
does he need immunity from?
Given the givens
in this case,
the D.A. felt
he had to offer that deal.
Now, I know the media
has broached the possibility
of Adam being involved somehow
in the Balloon Man's crimes,
but we haven't confirmed
any of that yet.
So how long do we wait for
you to confirm something?
Um, an hour, a day, a week?
I mean, he just said we only
have till noon tomorrow.
Mr. Castillo...
Has anybody asked Adam Kemper
what he wants?
He's 19-- an adult.
If he was really some sort of
partner to this monster,
then isn't it possible
that he wants to go back?
Victims of horrific abuse
are often protective
of their abusers.
It doesn't mean we should
send them back for seconds.
GREGSON:
No, listen,
the immunity deal
is on the table.
Then why hasn't
he taken it?
Because he's been
traumatized.
He's hardly speaking,
even to his own parents.
Come on.
If anything happens
to our daughter,
your head is the one we're going
to be calling for in the press.
(door closes)
So now what?
We go back to the files.
We see if there's
any clue that we missed
as to where Abbott is
keeping the girl.
That's one option.
You have another?
When Adam's parents
hired a lawyer,
they put a wall
between him and the NYPD.
No cop can talk to him.
No cop.
That's interesting.
And where is he now?
What?
I'm sore.
Only did about a thousand
squats last night.
Listen, I wanted to thank
you for all of your help.
Well, always happy
to listen.
No, no, no,
actually, Watson,
I was the one who
listened last night,
and I heard someone who
was willing to accommodate
the difficult process
of a difficult person
for the greater good.
It's a rare quality,
in my experience.
I may even listen to you
again in the future.
Not your sobriety
twaddle, of course.
Just your thoughts
on cases.
Thank you
for seeing me, Adam.
You're the only
one who gets it.
(chuckles softly)
Well, you know by now we've
identified him, don't you?
Samuel Abbott?
Are you worried about him?
He's my dad.
Is that why you've been hesitant
to sign the immunity deal?
Would you turn in your dad?
I'd trade my dad for a Tic Tac,
but that's my dad, not yours.
The sooner we find him,
the better off he'll be.
He hasn't hurt
Mariana Castillo yet.
You loved him...
but you didn't love
what he did.
I can tell.
He did make you help
with the others, didn't he?
He's my dad.
That doesn't mean
it wasn't hard.
Is that why you didn't want
to sign the deal?
Because you don't feel
you deserve it?
I never...
I never knew why it was
so important to him.
But I loved him.
And when he asked me to take--
help take the others,
then I told him I'd do that.
It's okay.
No, it isn't.
Nothing's okay.
I'm so confused.
I don't know what
I'm supposed to do.
(sniffling)
You told me the other day
that you'd never lie to me.
That's right.
So tell me.
If I sign that deal,
and if I tell you
where you can find him,
do you think it'll make up
for the things I've done?
No, I don't.
Six other children are dead,
thanks to your dad.
To whatever degree
you assisted him,
you will never get their blood
off your hands.
But that doesn't mean
you shouldn't try.
Okay.
I'll sign the papers.
I'll tell you where we live.
That's where
you'll find the girl.
(loud banging)
(gasps)
Drop the gun and let her go.
Now!
Tell Adam I'm sorry.
(gunshot)
(indistinct radio transmissions,
camera shutter clicking)
Mariana's okay.
She's terrified.
She hasn't been hurt.
You can go home, get some rest.
You okay?
He wasn't what I was expecting.
Who?
Samuel Abbott.
He dominated Adam.
I was expecting
a more virile man.
Just seems a bit...
feeble.
And that back brace.
WATSON:
Three scars.
Means major surgery, multiple
operations, fused vertebrae.
Makes sense that
he would've needed Adam
to help him get around.
(wind whistling)
Do you hear that?
What?
What...?
WATSON:
My God.
This is where
Adam slept?
(wind whistling)
What's wrong?
That man out there, Abbott,
is not the Balloon Man.
HOLMES:
Hello, Adam.
Mr. Holmes,
what are you doing here?
Thought it was time for
another one of our little chats.
How did you get into my room?
Through the window.
Somehow I managed to open it
without slicing my hand.
You said that...
you cut your hand
trying to open a window
in your room.
Your room.
Not Samuel Abbott's.
So imagine my surprise
when I saw your room today.
Two lamps, proper bed,
television.
Virtual palace
compared to Samuel's room.
All he had was a stained
mattress and a tattered sheet.
No, you're talking
about my room.
That's where he made me sleep.
No,
don't lie to me, Adam,
not again.
You told me when we met
that you injured your hand
trying to open a window
in your room,
the master bedroom.
That's where
the broken pane was.
Samuel Abbott
was not the Balloon Man.
You were.
Mr. Holmes, I-I...
I examined the pillows
in the larger room--
I found nothing
but short, dark hair--
your hair.
On the pillows
in the smaller room,
I found nothing
but Samuel's hair--
stringy and gray.
You occupied the master bedroom
because you were the master.
(quiet sigh)
You tricked me, Adam.
That doesn't happen very often.
I thought you were a dullard.
You're actually...
quite brilliant.
It must take
a huge intellect
for a boy to turn the tables
on the man who abducted him.
You have no idea.
Whose idea
was it to take more children?
Was it his... or was it yours?
I'd just turned 14;
I was lonely.
No. What you wanted was
to make someone else the victim,
hurt them...
like you'd been hurt.
No, you're forgetting
the parents.
They're the ones
that I got to see on TV,
crying, begging
the monster
who took their son or daughter
to give them back.
See, when Samuel took me,
it was very difficult at first.
I had to put up
with a lot.
But he did let me watch TV,
and so I got to see
my parents on the news
at least once a day, pleading
with Samuel
to let me go.
And the funny
thing was,
he wasn't
the least bit affected.
But I was.
You got off on it.
I really found myself.
And as for how I turned
the tables on him,
let's just say
it's not very difficult
when your captor has an IQ
south of 90.
Psychological abuse
followed by physical--
all very standard.
And the trade
he proposed yesterday--
Mariana for me--
wasn't even his idea.
It was a
contingency plan.
If I ever got caught,
he was supposed
to use the hostage that we had,
or take a new one,
to secure my release.
And the idiot didn't even have
a clue that the police
would never go for that
in a million years.
But you knew it
would give them incentive
to offer you an immunity deal.
Must have taken
everything you had
not to jump on that deal
the first time it came up.
Are you here to kill me,
Mr. Holmes?
Because I
have to admit
I find the possibility
very... exciting.
I'm gonna go brush my teeth now.
I don't think you're gonna
be here when I get back.
If it's any
consolation,
I don't think I'm gonna stay
in this city much longer.
I think it's time
to move someplace else,
meet new people.
I'm gonna miss our little chats.
WATSON: I just got an e-mail from my
friend from the D.A.'s office.
He said the language
from the immunity agreement
is pretty ironclad. "Adam Kemper
. is immune from prosecution."
"For any crimes committed
in consort with Samuel Abbott,
aka the Balloon Man."
Yes, I'm quite familiar
with the phrasing.
I've been reviewing it myself.
(sighs) Look, what that
kid did is... disgusting.
I hate the fact that he's
out there in the world.
But you did make
a difference.
You saved Mariana,
and you told the police
what kind of person
Adam Kemper really is.
I handed a psychopath
a get-out-of-jail-free card.
You're not the only one
he fooled.
If you're trying to blow off
steam, squats would be cheaper.
Easier on the decor, too.
I can't.
I overdid last night
and pulled a muscle.
My back's been sore all day.
I said a hundred squats,
not a thousand.
Back pain.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Dear sweet...
back pain.
(birds chirping)
Morning, Adam.
(exhales)
You picturing
those two begging for
their son's life?
No, it's nice out-- I'm
just passing the time.
You look kind of tired.
I'm getting that
a lot lately.
Listen, before you leave town,
I wanted to ask you
about William Crawford.
Your fifth victim.
Parents called him Billy.
Ah.
You abducted him on April 3,
2009.
Right, yeah.
Blond boy.
He cried a lot.
Well, yes, I'm sure you
could reminisce all day.
Still, not your
cleanest work.
The police found
his body on April 7.
Yeah, we buried him
deeper after that.
Actually, let me be
clear about that,
in case you have somebody listening
to our conversations.
Mr. Abbott made me bury
them deeper after that.
Whoever had the idea,
I think it was a good one,
because the police found skin
under William's fingernails.
Definitely came from
one of his attackers.
We ran it against Samuel
Abbott's DNA this morning.
And let me guess
it didn't match.
Is this supposed
to be scaring me?
It's probably mine.
So what?
I have an immunity deal.
Yes, you do.
You cannot be prosecuted
for any crimes committed, quote,
"in consort with," unquote,
the Balloon Man.
Thing is...
Samuel Abbott broke
three vertebrae in his back
on March 23, 2009.
That's why he couldn't work
as an exterminator anymore.
That's why he wore a back brace.
The surgery had him
in hospital for three weeks.
I believe he was
in traction the entire time.
Difficult to abduct
and murder a young boy
when you're feeling well,
I'd imagine.
From a hospital bed,
I'd say it was impossible.
I have an immunity deal.
For crimes committed in consort
with Samuel Abbott.
But you took William Crawford
on your own, didn't you?
What happened?
You get bored while
your playmate was in hospital?
Actually, you know what,
don't tell me,
'cause... I don't care.
Are those for me?
I called them right after your
parents told me you were in the park.
You're welcome
to try and run.
I've recently started
developing my core, you know?
Could use a bit of a workout.
Oh, no. A fair fight's
not really your speed, is it?
It was only one murder.
And Samuel
abused me.
I'll be out soon.
(birds chirping)
♪ ♪
♪ They told me
not to smoke drugs ♪
♪ Said I'd wind up in prison ♪
What are you doing?
Depriving you
of all stimuli.
It's time for you to get some sleep.
What?
No. No, no, no, no. No.
Right after you solve a case
you're flushed with success.
We should double down on work.
We?
You, me...
Angus.
Some combination of the three.
You already know
I favor you. Mm?
Hey!
No! No! This is...
Right now I'm
full of energy,
ideas, momentum.
What kind of tea is that?
Drowsy-time tea.
It detoxifies and cleanses the system.
Now is the moment
when a true detective
digs into his old files.
You see everything
with a new light. You'll see.
I'm gonna solve three
cases by nightfall.
♪ You and me,
I had to get out ♪
♪ And make a deal ♪
♪ And learn to know
how it feels, but that... ♪
♪ Out of my system... ♪
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
www.tvsubtitles.net