(keypad beeping)
♪
(doorbell rings)
Hey, are you gonna
get that or...
(TV playing quietly)
Hey, Sherlock's asleep.
I wasn't sure
if I should get the door.
I'm Gwen-- you're
the companion, right?
Yes.
(doorbell rings)
Guess I should
go get dressed.
(laughs)
(doorbell rings)
WOMAN: Sorry, I wasn't
sure if you wanted me
to get...
Oh, you're
not Sherlock.
You're the companion, right?
Yes.
I'm Olivia.
It's nice to meet you.
I think I just met your sister.
Did she mention what time our
car service is getting here?
(doorbell rings)
No.
You should get the door.
There's crepes
downstairs if you want.
Good morning.
Well, if you must know, Watson,
the Lynch sisters and I enjoy
a mutually beneficial
relationship.
"If I must know?"
I didn't ask.
I need to study the difference
between two specimens born
into the world with exactly
the same genetic material.
In the Lynches case,
there are seven major ones.
And they get...
I... didn't... ask.
(doorbell rings)
If that's for me,
I'm not here.
I'm going back to bed,
after I see the Lynches off.
Good morning.
Does, um,
Sherlock Holmes live here?
I was referred here
by an old colleague
of his in London.
He said I might have
to try more than once.
Good advice.
Would you please tell him
that I need
to speak with him?
Why don't you
tell him yourself.
Casterly Rock Security.
The world's foremost maker
of bank vaults.
And you, Mr. Erlich, are the
president and head engineer.
I am familiar with
your work. Crepe?
Bye, Sherlock.
If you know our work,
you know that
we introduced a new flagship
product in 2009.
The Leviathan.
Yes.
The safe that you marketed
as impregnable.
Did you people learn nothing
from the Titanic?
Bye, Sherlock.
Your company introduced a
supposedly unbreakable safe
in 2009, and then paid
the price for your hubris
when The Leviathan was plundered
within the calendar year.
Thank you.
The four men who robbed
that bank, they were brilliant.
A once-in-a-lifetime assembly
of criminal talent.
Now, eventually all four
were caught and convicted,
but none of them talked.
We did what we could to improve
the product, but the chance
of another four criminals
that bright collaborating again?
And yet, here you sit.
The Svalbard Diamond Exchange
was robbed last night.
They're missing
$40 million in stones.
Stones protected
by your vault.
The Leviathan has
a seven-figure price tag.
If somebody finds out that
another one's been compromised
and we don't know how,
we're done.
Well, the police must be looking
into who robbed your vault.
I take it the "how"
is where I come in?
I think that there must have
been a fifth conspirator.
Someone the other thieves
never told us about.
Poppycock.
The height of
intellectual vanity.
If one group of people
can figure out
to get past your vault,
so can a second...
No, you don't understand.
We have six layers
of bleeding-edge security,
redundancy at every step.
And if a second group can,
so can a third.
If you want to know the answer,
just take me
to the diamond exchange.
We'll talk fee
on the way,
although I'm not sure I have
a rate for a job that's only
gonna take an hour or two.
HOLMES:
The security upstairs is
rather rudimentary.
I take it anything of value
is stowed in the vault,
after hours.
Mr. Erlich.
The police said
that your consultant
can't see the vault
till they're done.
I'm also a consultant
with the NYPD, Mister...?
Batonvert, David Batonvert.
I'm the floor manager here.
I can assure you I know
how to conduct myself
at a crime scene, Mr. Batonvert.
Your name means
"green stick" in French.
Uh, yeah?
So, you have a motion sensor
embedded in the ceiling,
a light sensor on the wall.
Cardboard box can take care
of the motion sensor.
The light detector they would
mask with simple black tape.
They made short work
of that lock.
Body heat sensor in the ceiling
could be coated with hair spray,
buy a little time,
which brings us to...
the door itself, yes.
She is beautiful, hmm.
This lock is not pickable.
That key is, what, a foot long?
The tumblers are weighted
so they cannot be manipulated
with a pick.
You could, of course,
put a tiny camera
on this fire extinguisher.
If you knew
an excellent locksmith,
you could provide
an image of the key,
have it duplicated.
Clever, but we
already knew that.
Ten-digit access code?
Yes, it's provided by
a random number generator
that's hardwired
into the system.
The code changes
every two minutes.
Who has the code?
It appears on a key fob
that the owner carries.
If you want to get in there,
he's got to read it to you.
He's in Gstaad right now.
He's had the fob on him
the whole time.
You could attack
the random number generator,
make it spit out a pattern,
so you could predict the code.
The number generator
is working perfectly.
I'm gonna need
a little time with this.
(keypad beeping)
What are you doing down here?
Stress testing the keypad.
You think there'd be some tell
in the keys themselves.
No, I mean, what are you
still doing down here?
You said you were gonna
be gone two hours.
It's been all day.
Has it?
How stubborn are you
gonna be about this?
Uh, excuse me?
We're closing now.
Green Stick, do you want
your diamonds back or not?
(gasps)
Oh, she thinks she's
a clever one, doesn't she?
Who's she?
Her.
What time is it?
She generates an ocean
of pure randomness,
and she wants you
to just lose hope and drown
in all those numbers,
but I can see the horizon line.
I can tread water.
Stop.
It is 2:00 in the morning.
You've been down here for
almost, what, 17 hours?
So?
So.
I'm supposed to meet my mother
for brunch in the morning.
Not spending the night in a bank vault.
So, go then.
I'm not gonna leave you
down here like this either.
In A.A., they'd say
you're on a dry drunk.
You're indulging in all
the obsessions of addiction
without actually using drugs,
so are you gonna admit
that you can't think your
way past that vault door
or am I gonna have to
smash the fire alarm
and get us both
dragged out of here?
You're absolutely
right, Watson.
I can sometimes disappear into
the rabbit hole of my psyche.
Okay, good, then
you're ready to go.
Would you mind terribly
if I just tried
one more idea before we leave?
(groans)
It'll only take a minute.
Fine.
(glass shatters)
What are you doing?!
Oh, my God, put that down!
Put that down!
Before you say anything,
I would like to remind you
that I'm holding an ax.
♪ Elementary 1x10 ♪
The Leviathan
Original Air Date on December 13, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
Did you give the people
at Casterly Rock
my cell phone number
as your contact info?
Well, I didn't want
them to call me.
Yeah, well, they're wondering
who took an ax to their vault.
Apparently the repair bill's
gonna be huge.
Cost of doing business.
They'll get over it
when I figure this out.
We need to figure out
who broke into the safe;
that's the way that we'll learn
how it happened.
It wasn't an inside job.
Everyone at Casterly
Rock who knew
how to get into that
thing has given an alibi.
And I can't see how
the original thieves
would've needed
a fifth conspirator.
The four of them had
all the tools they needed
between them.
No, obvious what happened.
One of the original team
sold the recipe
for breaching The Leviathan
to an outside party.
That's obvious?
When you've eliminated the
impossible, whatever remains,
however improbable,
is the truth.
And what's impossible here
is that you couldn't break
into the safe, but
someone else could.
In other worlds, you are the
smartest man in the world.
Waiting for you to chime in
and say that's ridiculous.
You'd think it would be
easy to get one of the four
original team to admit that
they sold the secret on.
But Carter Averill,
the man who organized the heist
died in prison last year,
and the other three have yet
to respond to my request
for a visit.
(phone ringing)
You should answer that.
Tell them it was
a necessary part of my process.
What are my keys doing here?
They weigh
the right amount.
And enjoy brunch
with your mother.
I hadn't realized
you were still so eager
to impress her.
You're dressed like
you're going to a job interview,
not brunch with
a loved one.
(speaking Mandarin)
Okay, I was still
reading that.
I told them to bring us
whatever's freshest.
So, I'm in the cab
on the way over,
and guess who I hear from.
(phone ringing)
Do you have to take that?
No. Go on.
Your brother called.
He called me; do you know
how rare that is?
I haven't spoken to Oren
in, what, two months?
He's coming to the city.
And he's
bringing Gabrielle.
Wow.
He tried to cut his trip short
in order to come back
for dinner with us tomorrow
night, but it didn't work out.
Wait, tomorrow night?
Mm-hmm.
Mom, you know about
my job, right?
I mean, I can't just
leave my client alone.
This is your brother, Joan.
Can't your client just get
a different babysitter
for tomorrow night?
"Babysitter."
Okay, here we go.
(phone ringing)
I didn't mean it that way.
You know, I'm just
gonna get that,
because it's just gonna...
Mm.
Hey, everything okay?
HOLMES:
Excellent, actually.
Don't come back
to the brownstone.
Meet me at Sing Sing Prison
at 2:30.
Why do you want me to meet you
at Sing Sing?
Charles Briggs, the lock-pick
from the original team
of thieves--
he's agreed to sit down with us.
Okay.
Okay, I'll see you there.
Sing Sing, the prison?
(door buzzes)
BRIGGS: You said you want to know
how we got
into Leviathan.
And you think
for some reason,
even though I kept my mouth shut
during the trial,
I'm going to tell you.
You did agree to see me,
which implies
you have a price.
You're one of the
best lock-pickers
in the world,
and I collect
expertise, Mr. Briggs,
people to help me with
my consultancy work
on an as-needed basis.
I think I could find a use
for a mind as lively as yours.
You want me to work
for the cops?
I want to offer you a
chance to use your brain.
I suspect
it'll be the only
such offer you get
for the rest of
your natural life.
How did you get past
The Leviathan door,
and who did you
sell your secret to?
I don't know exactly
how we got in.
We were specialized.
I was responsible for getting
past the outer door.
Averill figured out the code,
but never told the rest of us
how he did it.
After he got sick, he told me
someone got in touch with him.
Averill said this guy wanted
to know how he did it,
and he was willing to pay.
If you're saying
that somebody else
broke into one
of those vaults,
my guess is Carter saw
an opportunity
to get a little money
for his family before he died,
told the guy his secret.
Who was it?
I only know an alias.
Even if you never find this guy,
which you won't...
...is that enough
to land me this gig?
The guy who Averill said
got in touch with him,
everyone just calls him...
Le Chevalier.
WATSON:
So let me get this straight.
This Le Chevalier guy,
he's a thief
who's allegedly stolen
an original copy
of Shakespeare's first folio,
a collection
of ancient Greek coins...
And Van Gogh's Pietà,
among things.
And no one can give us
a description of him?
No one knows if he's European,
American, a leprechaun.
You're making a point
of some kind.
Sounds like a fairy tale.
Well, some
people think so.
But all five robberies
attributed to Le Chevalier
remain unsolved.
And you asked Charles Briggs
for the name of the man
who bought the secret,
and he gives you a legend,
a man who might not
even exist.
You know,
this is a snipe hunt.
Briggs said it himself.
No one's ever even come close
to finding him.
You're forgetting
one thing, Watson.
I've never gone
looking for him.
WATSON:
This painting was stolen
the same night
that the Aster Museum
finally unveiled
it to the public.
Now, most people think
it was Le Chevalier.
If he's real,
this guy's got style.
This man is real.
There is a singular sensibility
at work here.
You can't just...
sell these things
on the black market.
They're too unique for that.
Hmm.
Who's that?
HOLMES:
That is Peter Kent.
He is head
of the Kent Philanthropic Trust
and leader
of the fundraising drive
that led to the acquisition
of The Pietà.
Look at his cufflinks.
They're fashioned from
silver tetradrachms.
They're Greek coins.
Now... look at the coins
Le Chevalier stole.
WATSON:
They're the same.
HOLMES:
That's Le Chevalier.
Le Chevalier may be
the stuff of legend,
but Peter Kent
is listed in the phone book.
WOMAN:
I'm sorry.
I'm a little confused.
You're here to speak
with Peter Kent?
Yeah, tell him it's
about Greek tetradrachms.
He'll know what I mean.
Is that a real Hopper?
Yeah, they're
all original.
You could buy an island
with the art on these walls.
Except that.
That's a lithograph,
worth maybe $40.
He wouldn't be so brazen.
What are you doing?!
I give you
Van Gogh's Pietà.
We found Le Chevalier.
What in God's name
are you doing?
You're not Peter Kent.
No, he's my father.
He's also a thief,
as you can see.
He stole The Pietà,
and two nights ago,
he robbed the Svalbard
Diamond Exchange.
Two nights ago?
I know this may come
as a bit of a shock,
but I assure you,
that painting
is genuine.
I don't know anything
about that,
but I'm positive
my father didn't
steal anything two nights ago.
My father had a
stroke two years ago.
He hasn't spoken or stood
in more than 18 months.
You were right.
Charles Briggs sent
us on a snipe hunt.
I'll tell you what.
I won't be using Charles Briggs
as a consultant
anytime soon.
I can't believe I got on
the subway with a Chopard watch.
There are 200 carats
of diamonds on that thing.
I don't even want to know
how much it costs.
The watch is
$25 million.
The Pietà almost
twice that,
if recent auctions
are anything to go by.
Got away with
it, didn't we?
Neither one of us wanted to
put a stroke victim in jail,
and Peter Kent's son doesn't
really want the world
to know what his
father did for a hobby.
Yeah, it's the best
solution for all parties.
I'd like to hear you
explain that in court.
"Your Honor, it's true.
We abetted in grand larceny."
Court, yes.
Well done, Watson.
What?
There was a trial.
When the first heist team
was arrested,
three of them
took plea bargains.
But Carter Averill,
the organizer,
he tried his luck at trial.
All the details
of the original crime,
they were aired in court,
and no one knew exactly
how the foursome got
into The Leviathan,
but it's worth going
over the transcripts.
There would have been
expert witnesses,
summaries of fact,
someone could have
pieced together the solution.
What? Why are you looking
at me like that?
Because I think the only reason
you're clinging
to this copycat theory
is because you couldn't
figure it out.
I'm playing the probabilities.
That's what I always do.
So, some priceless artifacts
just came into your possession,
and the fewer questions I have
about said artifacts the better.
Correct.
And this just happened
to be on the day
that you were looking
into Le Chevalier,
and this happens to be
the stuff that he stole.
And the culture will be grateful
for their return.
Mm-hmm.
Y-You're not leaving that?
Oh. (chuckles)
No, this is just something
I picked up for my place.
WATSON:
I'm not okay with this.
You don't like
where it's hanging?
You stole a $50
million painting.
I did not steal it;
I'm just delaying its return.
If I'm going to spend
the evening
reading court transcripts,
I might as well do it
in the company
of a masterpiece.
It really ties
the room together.
Well, you're gonna take
that back to the Aster Museum
(phone ringing)
first thing in the morning.
What's my phone doing up here?
(ringing continues)
Hey, Oren.
Joan.
I'm so excited to see you.
I miss you, sis.
I miss you, too,
but didn't Mom tell you
I'm on a job?
She did,
but I just got your text.
It said you're coming.
From me?
Yeah, you're coming to dinner.
You're bringing your client.
My client?
No, I... well...
Oh, come on, Joan.
Tell me you'll be there.
Uh, I... Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I'll be there.
We'll talk tomorrow, okay?
Okay. Love you.
Bye.
I put a lock code on here
to prevent you from
sending out texts.
I was hired to breach
The Leviathan.
Do you think I wouldn't be able
to get into your phone?
Yeah, well, you're not
gonna meet my family.
Aren't I? I don't know.
I'm not sure I can be
without your company
for two hours tomorrow night.
Feeling a little relapse-y.
(gasps)
You're only using that word
because you know
that I can't leave you alone
if you say "relapse."
You just want to meet
my family so you can
put them under a microscope.
Nonsense. You search
your conscience, Watson.
If you're really comfortable
going out for dinner
while I dream
of chasing the dragon,
then so be it.
I have a transcript to read.
HOLMES:
Good morning.
Coffee,
yogurt, assorted fruits.
Thanks.
Seven minutes for you
to eat and drink,
23 minutes for you
to shower and get dressed,
should get us
to the property clerk's office
just as it opens.
Why are we going to the
property clerk's office?
That's where they keep
Exhibit C.
Exhibit C
from Carter Averill's trial.
I want to have a look at it.
The jury looked at it
three separate times
while they were deliberating.
Well, isn't that what
the jury's supposed to do,
look at the exhibits?
This is a scrap of paper
from the trash bag
that the thieves' landlord
gave to the police.
It's a simple,
handwritten note,
a scrawled coffee order
with the names of the criminals
written next to the drinks
that they wanted.
Apparently, they made
a Starbucks run
while they were planning
the heist.
So? Thieves drink coffee, too.
Not my point.
The prosecution used it to prove
that the four men
were working together.
After that's done, it's hardly
a trove of information, is it?
Why would the jury need to look
at a coffee order three times?
(sighs)
WATSON:
That looks like a coffee order.
Three of them ordered soy.
I'm surprised they were
so health-conscious.
That looks like something
your printer
spits out when it's trying
to test to see if it works.
It looks like sheer nonsense.
That's what it is supposed
to look like.
It's a programming language
called "Malbolge."
It was designed
to be impenetrable.
The language's creator named it
after the eighth circle of hell
in Dante's Inferno.
Now, there are few people
in the world
who can even recognize Malbolge
as anything other
than gibberish.
Fewer still
who can write software
using it.
I learned about the language
from a consultant
I used in London.
She should be able
to get us a translation soon.
The important thing is
it's a message.
It was hidden in plain sight
throughout the trial.
Do you think someone
from the jury recognized it?
Why else would they ask to see
a coffee order
again and again, hmm?
Here you are. Justin Guthrie.
Unemployed at the time
of the trial,
but listed
his previous occupation
as "software engineer."
Shall we see if he's familiar
with Malbolge?
So what do we do
if this guy Guthrie says
he doesn't know what
you're talking about?
We can start
by seeing
if he's got any
diamonds lying around.
(phone chimes)
That's it.
They attacked the
random number generator.
That does not say,
"they attacked
the random number generator."
It's an algorithm,
Watson.
This is a translation
of the coded Malbolge,
sent by my contact
in London.
This is how
the first team
of thieves got into
The Leviathan.
The vault's software
is designed to spit out
ten random digits
every two minutes.
This makes it
impossible to predict
the access code at
any given moment.
The genius of the original
plan is this algorithm.
They hacked the software,
fed the equation into it.
It spits out
escalating multiples
of the number pi
every two minutes.
Pi is infinite,
so if you take a
ten-digit sample,
the numbers still
appear random.
But if you know
the algorithm,
you can predict
the code.
Yes. Even after you leave,
it still looks like
the software is
functioning perfectly, hmm?
Justin Guthrie must have
translated the Malbolge,
realized that he had the key
for cracking The Leviathan.
Well, any Leviathan.
So, a guy on the jury
planned a $40-million heist?
Well, he had help,
obviously.
But that's exactly
what he did.
When you've eliminated
the impossible,
Watson, whatever
remains...
Yeah, you said
that already.
Officer, we need to get
into the building.
Sorry, pal, no can do.
This is an active
investigation.
Yes. I'm a consultant
with the NYPD,
and I need to speak to
one of the tenants.
His name is
Justin Guthrie.
You said Guthrie?
Yes. Shall I spell
it for you? G...
No, but considering he's
the one we're here for,
you might want to talk
to one of the detectives.
Mr. Guthrie jumped out
the window
of his apartment
a little while ago.
(garbled radio transmission)
(light melody playing)
So the precinct detective says
this is a suicide,
but you think that he stole
$40 million in diamonds
and then got killed
behind it?
So what's the story?
(music stops)
Obviously, a violent
altercation took place.
Blood evidence.
Myself and Miss Watson
found it
and examined it closely.
Spatter pattern indicates
it's a high forced event.
He's saying the blood came from
someone who was hit in the nose.
Okay. It's worth
looking into.
I still don't see the connection
to that robbery.
I was just thinking about
that when you arrived.
The answer, of course,
lies in those vases.
These two has three layers
of decorative rock,
each one
a different color.
This one has two layers,
but the mineral residue
on the glass indicates
that it was full
till very recently.
Many of the stones stolen
from the Svalbard Exchange
were uncut diamonds.
They happen to look exactly
like decorative rocks.
Now, if you'd just stolen some,
this vase would be
an ideal hiding place.
I'm guessing that
whichever co-conspirator
just relieved Mr. Guthrie
of his share
of the diamonds
thought the same thing.
He was, however,
in a hurry.
He might have missed one.
You're telling us
that's a...?
Uncut diamond.
Let's get some more
detectives down here.
I want to start
a full-scale canvass.
Looks like we have
a murder on our hands.
Look, it's almost 6:00.
We have to start getting ready.
Oh, right.
Dinner with your family.
Well, as you said, this is now
a murder investigation.
You'll understand
if I can't make it.
Absolutely.
HOLMES: And I would never
have been able
to prove that you
were a murderer.
(laughter)
Joan, you're here.
Excellent.
I was just telling your
family about my work.
Hi there.
This lovely young lady
is Gabrielle.
She's your brother's girlfriend;
soon, I expect, fiancée.
It's so nice to
finally meet you.
It's so nice
to meet you.
Oren talks about you all the time.
(chuckles)
(quietly):
What happened to,
"this is a murder
investigation"?
In a bit of a lull
right now, actually.
We're awaiting
the results
of the DNA tests
on the blood.
And I saw a chance to spend
some time with your family,
and I took it.
Joan, is it true you helped
prove the CIO of Canon Ebersole
had a secretary who killed
five people?
Uh, not really.
I just helped out a little.
She was instrumental
in solving that case.
She also went to the trouble
of saving my life.
Quite a promising detective
in her own right.
I'm not a detective.
I just, I'm along for
the ride for a while.
You're being modest.
That's not the only case
she's helped me solve.
Hard to picture
what she does, isn't it?
"Sober companion."
When I first heard
that term,
I couldn't imagine what it
entailed, and I'm an addict.
(laughter)
She practices quite a
unique specialty, your daughter.
She rebuilds lives
from the ground up.
You can measure her success
in careers restored.
In my case, criminals
caught and in lives saved.
Interesting.
Never thought of it like that.
Of course you haven't.
You've raised
a modest daughter.
She would never
say such a thing.
Shall we order?
I hear the rabbit
is a-ma-zing.
I know you're gonna
blow this off,
but I'm gonna say it
anyway: thank you.
I've never been able to make
my family understand what I do.
Yes, well, I meant very
little of what I said.
There's the blowing-off part.
I know my audience.
I simply told them what
they wanted to hear.
They're nice people,
your family,
but they are, at their
core, conventional.
You make an effort to
appear conventional,
but I know, Watson, you share
my love of all that is bizarre
and outside the humdrum
routine of ordinary life.
Your family will never
understand this,
so I gave them some words
that they would understand.
What?
I'm just curious
as to who Justin Guthrie
might have collaborated with
to rob the
diamond exchange.
I've been sifting through
his phone in my downtime.
That's the dead guy's phone?
Isn't that evidence?
Yeah, well, I will give it
back when I'm finished.
He stored three phone numbers
in his notes section.
Each one has just a first name
next to it:
Jeremy, Amelie, Alex.
These are the names
of three people
with whom he served
on the jury.
So they kept in touch.
Have you served
jury service?
Did you have
any desire
to see those people
again when it was over?
(opera music playing loudly)
It's 3:00 in the morning!
(volume decreases)
It's nearly finished.
Don't turn it down.
I'm basking.
(volume increases)
Can't you bask
in the morning?
(music stops)
It's this case, Watson.
It renews one's faith
in the profession.
It's a life of boundless
surprises, detective work.
Do I have to find you
a drug test?
These are the four men who broke
into The Leviathan
in 2010.
Now, we've already met
Charles Briggs, lock-pick
and locksmith extraordinaire.
This is Vance Paulson.
He was the
inside man.
The late Carter Averill,
organizer of the crime,
genius.
He mastered everything from
computer coding
to surveillance software.
And, finally, David Retts,
PhD in electrical engineering.
Nothing about this is making me
want to bask.
I haven't got
to the good bit yet.
We already know
that Justin Guthrie's
programming skills
allowed him to perform much the
same function as Carter Averill.
Now let's meet
some of his fellow jurors.
Alex Wilson worked as
an electrical engineer
until his employer forced
early retirement on him.
Jeremy Lopez,
son of a locksmith.
Paid his way through school
by plying his father's trade.
So you're saying that Justin
Guthrie committed this robbery
with other members of the jury?
Probably started as a joke.
Jurors spend
a lot of time together.
Lots of idle chitchat, hmm?
They noted that between them,
they had the same skill set
as the thieves
they were trying.
Once Justin Guthrie spotted
the coded programming language,
things turned serious.
They realized
they'd been handed the recipe
for making millions of dollars.
So, who was the inside man?
This is Amelie Widomski,
a homemaker
from Roosevelt Island.
I couldn't make any sense
of it until I noticed
that she'd written her maiden
name on some paperwork.
Amelie Widomski was born
"Amelie Batonvert."
Green Stick.
The manager of
the Svalbard Diamond Exchange
is her brother.
Whether he was in on it
or whether she just used
the family connection to gain
access during working hours,
these are the four people
who robbed
the Svalbard Diamond Exchange
two days ago.
And one of them is killing
the others to keep the proceeds.
GREGSON: Okay, ten jurors,
two alternates.
The only surviving juror
we couldn't find is Alex Wilson.
That's the engineer.
You think he has something
to do with this, right?
So, assuming you're right
about what happened,
he's probably in the wind.
Seems like
he could be our guy.
Maybe, but I believe
our killer is standing
in that room.
That man is named
Jeremy Lopez.
Even from here, you can
see his face is injured.
You think Justin Guthrie
did that to him?
Should be easy enough
to find out.
(door opens)
Ladies and gentlemen, um,
so I'd like to start
by thanking you all
for fulfilling your civic duty.
The justice system called,
12 of you answered. Yes.
Unfortunately, it seems that
four of your number have become
criminals themselves,
and one of those four
is now a murderer.
Shocking, I know.
But we have
obtained a sample
of the murderer's blood.
Now it's a simple case
of comparing your DNA
to that sample,
and we'll have our killer.
Okay, you can start.
HOLMES:
Please, bear in mind,
we cannot force you
to give samples.
But you've already
demonstrated
your civic-mindedness
by serving as jurors,
and I'm sure that the innocent
amongst you will relish
the chance to help
catch a murderer.
If, however,
you recently
did murder Justin Guthrie,
you certainly should not
offer a sample.
Uh, that would be folly.
Everything all right, Mr. Lopez?
Fine, fine.
All right, everyone,
you can go now.
Thank you very much
for your time.
We'll, uh, keep some people
on Lopez and Amelie Widomski,
make sure they
don't try to flee.
Maybe he gave us that sample
because he knew if he didn't,
we'd know it was him.
(scoffs)
I know. He seemed
pretty confident.
Why would a killer just
hand off his DNA like that?
I don't believe he would.
BELL:
Captain.
We just heard from an officer
in Irvington, New Jersey.
Guy saw our BOLO
on Alex Wilson.
This cop swears he saw Wilson
couple days ago.
Gave us an address.
We need to find him.
I may have been wrong
about Jeremy Lopez,
and I doubt Amelie Widomski
could throw a man
out of a window,
so if Lopez is not our man,
then Alex Wilson must be.
(knocks)
NYPD! Open up!
Let's go.
Open up or we're coming in.
(flies buzzing)
Detective, uh,
I'm concerned there's no need
to look for Mr. Wilson inside.
Not with this many
coffin flies around.
Coffin flies?
Small, humpbacked members
of the Phoridae family.
They feed on decaying corpses.
They're congregating
on this cardboard.
(flies buzzing)
Looks like he's been
dead at least two days.
He didn't kill
Justin Guthrie yesterday.
Oh, good, you're back.
We just got the preliminary
DNA results
back from
Justin Guthrie's apartment.
It doesn't match Jeremy Lopez,
it doesn't match Alex Wilson.
It belongs to an Army chaplain
by the name of Audrey Higuerra.
What's her connection
to the jury?
As far as we know,
she doesn't have one.
HOLMES:
Seems rather noble,
this Audrey Higuerra,
doesn't she?
Very noble indeed.
I don't like her.
Is that because she's a chaplain
or because she has
a "Habitat For Humanity" sticker
in her window?
I don't like her
because she doesn't fit.
It was a beautiful theory,
not a hair out of place.
The first robbery, the team
of jurors-turned-criminals
who turned on each other
like a pack of rabid dogs.
But this Audrey
Higuerra--
she doesn't have any
connection to these people.
She doesn't
fit anywhere.
Well, we found her blood in
Justin Guthrie's apartment.
And someone once said
once you've eliminated
the impossible,
whatever remains, no matter
how improbable, is the truth.
Sounds like a windbag.
I don't see anything here
that supports the idea
that she was
a murderer.
HOLMES:
Quite the opposite.
If I could attribute
three miracles to her, I would
nominate her for sainthood.
Yeah, looks like she's got the
caring for the sick part down.
She nursed her sister
through cancer.
So, not only is Audrey Higuerra
not to be found in her own home,
she's not even in the country.
We just found her calendar.
Turns out, she was deployed
to Kabul a couple weeks ago.
That can't be.
We just found a fresh
blood sample, hers,
in Justin Guthrie's
apartment yesterday.
We're waiting
on the Army to confirm
that she's posted overseas,
but, I mean, look around.
Does it look like anyone's
been here recently?
Can I take back
everything I said
about eliminating
the impossible?
Why would you want to do that?
Because Audrey Higuerra's sister
died of leukemia.
And then once she was gone,
Audrey did
everything she could to help
people with the same disease.
I used to see this at the
hospital all the time.
They give them
to bone marrow donors.
HOLMES: Do you still
have a police detail
following Jeremy Lopez?
We called it off
when the DNA results came back.
You need to find him,
bring him in immediately.
I don't know
why I'm back here.
I already gave
you people my DNA.
Yeah, we had a little
problem with that.
Something went wrong
with one of the swabs.
If it's not too much trouble,
we'd like to get a blood sample.
It's a cleaner read.
I've already been very helpful.
Generous, even.
But, honestly,
I don't like needles.
I don't see why I should...
HOLMES:
There they are.
The evasions
and rhetorical curlicues
of a man with something to hide.
I don't have anything to hide.
You had leukemia; is
that correct, Jeremy?
Yeah. Five years ago.
I'm better now.
Good.
And you're better because of
a bone marrow
transplant, right?
Did you know that one
of the side effects
of a bone marrow transplant
is that your body
begins to manufacture cells
that bear the DNA of your donor?
Right.
And bone marrow
manufactures blood.
So you know that every
recipient of a transplant
walks around with the
DNA of their donor
coursing through
their veins.
But the DNA in your skin,
your hair, your saliva,
that's all your own.
The blood that we found at
Justin Guthrie's apartment,
it bears the DNA
of Audrey Higuerra,
but it came
from your body.
You knew that you could
give us a saliva sample,
because the DNA
wouldn't match the blood
that we found at
the crime scene.
I cannot believe that you are
dragging my illness into this.
You stole $40 million, and then
you murdered two people.
I'm leaving.
Don't call me.
Don't expect me
to cooperate.
Oh, we don't need
your cooperation.
What's that?
Court order.
Compels you to give us
a blood sample.
HOLMES:
We neglected to mention
that we had that
when we first came in.
Yes.
Well, we just didn't want
to deny ourselves the pleasure
of watching you squirm.
You give us
enough to arrest
Amelie Widomski for her part
in the robbery, and who knows?
Maybe a parole board
will see you before you're dead.
Such a shame.
Those bottles cost $500 apiece.
You'd think if they wanted
to thank me with champagne,
they'd go to the trouble
of finding out if I drink first.
Have a glass if you like.
You figured out Audrey Higuerra
was a bone marrow donor.
Pretty sure that's
not a good idea.
Is the smell
gonna bother you?
I suppose being proven right
is the best gift of all.
Hmm.
There was no genius
who independently
cracked The Leviathan.
It was a question
of copying the original team.
Ah.
So that means you still might be
the smartest person
in the world.
I would never suggest that.
Really?
I think that's the first time
I've ever heard you say
anything remotely modest.
It's not modesty.
There's just no reliable way
to test the hypothesis.
(doorbell rings)
Triplets?
Mom?
I know I'm not
supposed to come see you
while you're out on a job,
but you did give me your card
the other night.
I was hoping
to talk to my daughter.
HOLMES:
Mm, please, come in.
Thank you.
I'll leave you
two to chat.
It's, uh... nice.
I've never seen
anything like it,
but it seems like, uh,
it suits your client.
So, you just wanted to come over
here to see where I'm staying?
I know you think that I
don't like your new career.
To put it mildly.
You're right, I don't like it.
But not for the reasons
that you think.
I'm not happy
that you're a sober companion
because it never seems
to make you happy.
How do you know
what makes me happy?
I know because
you're my daughter.
(sighs)
After you left medicine,
after what happened with Liam,
I've always thought
that this job
was something that
you picked out of...
I don't know, out
of a sense of duty.
When you came to dinner
the other night,
when the two of you talked
about Sherlock's work,
I saw something
in you.
There was a spark.
A sense of
excitement.
I haven't seen that
in you in a long time.
You like
what he does.
Yes, okay, I enjoy it.
But I'm not a detective, Mom.
And I'm almost done
working with Sherlock,
and then it's on
to another client.
Will the next client
make you happy?
People find their paths
in the strangest of ways.
So sorry to interrupt.
I've just, I've seen
the most incredible thing
on the news.
I'm quite sure
you'd want to see it.
REPORTER: The police
are puzzled by the sudden
and unexplained return
of Vincent Van Gogh's
masterpiece, Pietà.
It was delivered
by courier to the head
of the Aster Museum
of Modern Art.
The NYPD is speculating
that the thief must have been
suffering from
a guilty conscience,
but the exact motive
for the return
remains a mystery.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
www.tvsubtitles.net