Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
♪
You ready to get
into the act?
I thought you'd never ask.
What's this? Intermission?
This is the part
where we take your stuff.
We're robbing you.
Well, I don't suppose
you could finish the show first.
How much money do you
keep in the house?
Never been robbed by people
in their underwear before.
Well, no. Was one chap,
but, uh, you are
much prettier.
You want to do this
the hard way?
Fine.
You know,
I'd heard rumors
of two prostitutes
who bind innocent whoremongers
and then rob them.
But to think that those
two women ended up in my home
on-on this very evening...
I suppose
I should thank you.
I usually investigate crimes
of a more... homicidal nature,
but it's been an uneventful
few days.
Gentlemen!
Just one question
before you leave.
Can I keep these?
I'm glad your bust
was such a success last night,
but this place still
smells like stripper.
Does it?
Yeah.
What's with the sword?
It's not a sword,
it's a singlestick.
Well, it looks like a sword.
In sword sports,
virtually the entire body
is a target.
In singlestick,
the players mark their distance,
plant their feet
and strike only at the pate.
You mean the forehead?
I mean the pate.
So, your docket's
still open today?
Sadly, yes.
Well, my landlord called.
I have to go
to my apartment this morning.
I think my subletter has been
throwing parties
or playing loud music
or something.
I confess, Watson.
I find your insistence
on maintaining your
own residence puzzling.
Hmm? As a live-in
sobriety counselor,
you could, in theory,
live rent-free
in the most expensive city
in the world indefinitely.
Why not embrace the fact
that you are a professional
nomad and give the place up?
'Cause I love my apartment.
It's my sanctum sanctorum.
When I get a job,
I sublet it,
and when I'm done, I go back.
And it's rent-controlled.
Those dolly-mops I
ensnared last night--
their performance
was quite invigorating.
I've got a bit to work out.
♪
Are you Krebs?
Yes.
Delivery for you.
Mr. Ennis, welcome
to Saint Gerard's.
Is my sister here yet?
She is, but per the agreement
your attorney made
with the state,
you won't be allowed
to see her while you're here.
Once you're inside,
we'll prep you for surgery.
We'll remove one kidney,
and then transplant it
into your sister.
Do you understand these terms
as I have explained them to you?
Man asked you
a question, Ennis.
Sorry. It's just, uh...
It's been a long time
since I've seen someone
so afraid of me.
I've missed it.
You're going to start
to feel drowsy, Mr. Ennis.
Would you please count down
from 20 for me?
Uh, 20...
19...
18...
17...
16...
Officer, I'll need you
to remove the cuffs
so we can sterilize
the abdomen.
Doctor?
I think there's something's
wrong with the IV.
The anesthetic
isn't entering the vein.
It's pooling beneath...
♪ Elementary 1x14 ♪
The Deductionist
Original Air Date on February 4, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
Howard Ennis killed two
corrections officers,
three doctors and a
nurse before he escaped.
I'm quite familiar
with the man.
He stalked women
via the Internet,
killed 13 of them
in New York and New Jersey
before he was arrested
eight years ago.
All of the victims, blonde,
all of them taller
than five foot, seven.
I remember this.
They called him the Peeler.
Ridiculous.
Why is it ridiculous?
Didn't he
skin people?
It's ridiculous to give the man
a clever little nickname.
It lends an air
of omniscience
that these people
in no way deserve.
You've met
serial murderers.
They're duller
than the Queen's jubilee.
Mouth-breathers and chronic
onanists, the lot of them.
Just a heads-up.
It's bad in there.
Like I said,
Ennis got the drop
on them somehow.
He pulled the IV line
intended to deliver the general
anesthetic out of his vein.
It pooled up beneath
the surface of his skin
instead of putting him to sleep.
He then slowed his heart rate
and his pulse rate
by practiced meditation
to fool the machines.
Attacked
when the time was right.
You just walked in here.
How could you
possibly know that?
Bloodstain.
Might as well
have a flashing arrow
pointing towards it.
There's blood everywhere,
of course, but...
this stain
is of particular interest.
It's clearly been diluted
with some other agent.
Chemical.
What's the most common
general anesthetic?
Propofol.
Propofol. I'll wager
we'll find that here.
This stain was created
when he yanked
the IV from his arm.
The heart rate?
The pulse? What...?
It's common knowledge,
the fakirs of Bangladesh
can meditate
their circulatory systems
to a virtual standstill.
This man was
shot in the head
so that his scrubs wouldn't
be stained with blood.
He took them, pointed his stolen
gun at whoever he needed to,
walked out the front door.
That's how he left.
I would certainly like to
know where Ennis is going,
and what he intends to do
with his newfound freedom.
Not sure if this
is going to be any help. Yo.
Ennis left a message behind.
"Shedir."
It's a star.
The traditional name
for Alpha Cassiopeia,
the southernmost star
of the Cassiopeia constellation.
No clue what
he's trying to tell us,
but our partners
are chewing on it.
Partners?
It's a serial case.
The FBI is here, too.
I came to understand
Howard Ennis
as well as any suspect
I've pursued.
What's she doing here?
She's the profiler who nailed
Ennis the first time around.
Kathryn Drummond.
Makes sense that
the Bureau wants her
to run point for them.
Captain, call for you.
You know her?
We worked together when
an American serial killer
came to London.
She's a buffoon.
All profilers are.
They're snake oil salesmen
who cast maladjusted
closet cases
as criminal geniuses
in the media.
The profilers, in turn,
can be super-geniuses
when the killers
are caught.
Isn't profiling part
of what you do?
I deduce.
Enormous difference.
Holmes.
Glad to see you landed
on your feet in New York.
I heard you had some
difficulties in London.
Nice to see you're
keeping tabs on me.
Yes. This is Joan Watson.
She accompanies me.
Helps keep those difficulties
from reoccurring.
Nice to meet you.
And you.
We are talking
about heroin, right?
Where's your captain?
I need the manpower to do
a four-quadrant search
of the neighborhood.
Did you know
that Patricia Ennis,
Howard Ennis's sister,
is a patient here?
Why not talk
to her first?
She was the one he was
ostensibly here to help,
so maybe she has some insight
as to where he's gone.
Oh, no. Wait.
Your book, that's right.
What was it called?
Profiles in Terror.
Yes, Ms. Drummond
wrote a book
about Howard Ennis
after she caught him.
Got into a spot of bother
when she speculated
about the sexual abuse
he must surely have suffered
at the hands
of his parents,
because they said
it was a lie.
Sued you for libel,
correct?
That got thrown out of court.
Nice to meet you.
This never would have
happened if...
if I hadn't gotten
Howard out of prison.
It's not your fault.
No, but after I got sick,
I asked the doctor
if there was
any other way.
I didn't want any part
of him inside of me.
But the waiting list
for the transplant
was so long.
The-the doctor
said that a...
a sibling would be
the best match.
Do you have any idea
where your brother
might have gone?
Until I asked him
for the kidney, we hadn't
spoken in years.
I have some letters
that he wrote me.
I could give you those
if you want.
Yes, that
would be very helpful.
Thank you.
Is she gonna be part
of the investigation?
She is, but you
won't have to...
So glad she's helping.
Howard needs to be stopped.
She did it once,
she can do it again.
Hi, Bruce.
Let me guess:
The air valve's making
that whistling sound again?
You know how this old radiator
gets in the winter.
Yeah, well,
when I hear it,
I know I'm home.
You know the Conklins
up on three?
Yeah, of course.
Their son's a
teenager now.
He went to certain...
Web pages.
So Mrs. Conklin
learns about it.
Checks the
search history
to see what her boy's
been exposed to.
She found a pornographic film
that was made right here,
in this apartment.
What are you talking about?
The guy you sublet the
apartment to-- Cooper?
He's been shooting
pornography here.
Hi.
I take it your meeting
did not go well.
You haven't asked
why I'm lying on the table.
You are clearly distracted.
My subletter filmed
a pornographic movie
in my apartment, so now
I'm getting evicted.
Well, I suppose now you can do
as I suggested:
live as a wandering nomad
of sobriety.
I don't want to be a
wandering nomad of sobriety.
I want my own space.
Well, perhaps I could
help you reclaim it.
No.
I mean...
I appreciate it;
it's just that
I want my apartment
the way it was before
it was... violated.
Yeah, I-I saw some of the
movie while I was there.
I don't think I could
live there again.
Why are you lying
on the table?
I'm looking at the stars.
That's Cassiopeia,
oriented as it appears now
in the night sky.
It fits precisely into a map
of Manhattan of that scale.
The first "X" is Shedir,
the first star.
Site of this morning's murders
in Greenwich Village.
That would put the second star
in Turtle Bay,
somewhere near the U.N;
the third star, Columbus Circle.
You get the idea.
This is a map
of where Ennis plans
to kill people.
This is important.
Did you tell anyone yet?
They're all very excited.
Resources being reallocated
as we speak.
Trouble is,
I think it's all bollocks.
Wait, you think you're wrong?
I think I cracked a code
that was intended to be cracked.
I think
he wants the police
directing resources
to these locations so he can,
I don't know, watch them.
Like mice running a maze
of his own design.
Oh, speaking of vermin.
What is it with you
and that woman?
It's obviously more
than just hating profilers.
If you're asking if we had sex,
the answer is yes, obviously.
Oh, so she's an ex?
More like a "C," C-plus at best.
We had an arrangement
while she was in London,
similar to the arrangement
I have with other women
here in New York.
We performed the act of love
loudly and repeatedly,
without any actual love,
or even any like.
I would describe it as an act
of self-love were it not
for the fact that she
was technically present.
I get it.
Now I would just prefer her
not to send
the police on an ego-driven
wild goose chase.
We updated the profile
to reflect our
latest thinking.
Captain, I know Ms. Drummond
is entitled to her say,
but before you imbibe
any profiling snake oil,
I would like to offer
my own assessment.
We're in the middle
of a meeting here.
Cassiopeia code
is certainly alluring.
Perhaps too alluring.
Howard Ennis
is not a spree killer.
I believe he is trying
to distract us.
He'll lie low, he'll
change his appearance,
but eventually,
he will pick up a blade,
and he will find
another young blonde.
Is that it?
Ms. Drummond's
latest profile.
Basically, it says
what you just said.
Ennis had to know
we'd break the code.
I didn't know you were capable
of that level of thinking,
but you have been exposed
to my methods, so...
I-I don't know what's
going on between you two,
but the important thing
to me is that
my top consultant
and the Bureau's top profiler
agree with each other.
The Public Employees Federation
sued the state...
... it argues that
the Health Department
overstepped its authority
by forcing employees
to be vaccinated
by November 30.
The Health Department
says it will fight...
Oh, God! Please...
Please... don't...
Will you do me a favor?
Would you mind taking
my picture with
your phone?
He walked into the store
and shot everyone here
except for the
one person
that actually fits
his victim profile.
You two said he
would lie low.
Change his appearance.
Is this what you call lying low?
I confess,
a crime like this
is out of character
for Howard Ennis.
But it doesn't invalidate
anything I wrote in my report.
The register was robbed.
Stands to reason
Howard Ennis would have
varied his routine
because he needed cash
to get out of town.
Poppycock.
Excuse me?
The desperate rhetorical
contortions of someone
with a pathological
need to be right.
Same old Sherlock Holmes.
Look around you.
Howard Ennis,
despite his many flaws,
is not a complete moron.
If money had been his goal,
why would he rob
a place like this?
What's the most he could
have gotten away with?
$200, maybe $300?
Doesn't take much to go on the lam.
Then explain
his decision to leave
that woman alive.
You can't, can you?
'Cause you and I
both know
that her
crossing his path
was like
a piece of chum
crossing the path
of a ravenous shark.
You think he's sending
a message?
I do.
I just don't know
what it is.
You told me you were a
documentary filmmaker.
Bruce talked to you.
No, Cooper, I just watch
a ton of porn.
Imagine my surprise
when I saw a bunch of people
having sex in my living room,
on my couch.
Okay, you're angry.
You totally should be.
You think?
Look, for what it's worth,
I really did want
to make a movie about
child soldiers in the Sudan.
But, what, a bunch
of porn actors broke in here
and forced you
to film them instead?
I needed the money.
I-I couldn't get anyone
to invest in the documentary,
so I had to turn back
to alternative filmmaking
to pay the rent.
Wait a second,
what do you mean, "turn back"?
You mean you made other "films"?
Not here.
But yeah.
I'm sorry.
Joan, seriously,
if I had the money,
I would have shot it
anywhere but here.
Man, did this
get screwed up!
After you took
the apartment back,
I was gonna ask you out!
How did it go
with your friend the auteur?
Didn't talk you
into a sequel, did he?
He's not my friend.
And he's getting kicked out,
same as me.
How's it going here?
Poorly.
I detached myself from the
Ennis manhunt several hours ago.
I thought I could be
more use to the police here.
Trying to decipher his game.
I was wrong.
That's mature.
Started out as a
simple mustache,
if you can believe it.
I know why you
don't like her.
You recall my aversion
to bile-spewing
pig-women?
"The Deductionist."
An article she wrote
for a psychiatric
journal ten years ago,
about a police consultant
she met
while on assignment in London.
A man she said was
"in possession
of a uniquely potent
deductive mind."
You seem genuinely
upset by her today.
So, I Googled her,
and I found the article.
She never referred to
you by name, but still,
some of the things
that she wrote...
When I first met
Kathryn Drummond,
she showed a modicum
of potential as an investigator.
So, aside from our
extracurricular exertions,
I tried to tutor her
in my methods.
She seemed quite amenable,
at the time.
Little did I know she was merely
interested in gaining
a better understanding of
the inner workings of my mind.
She was profiling you.
Well, that's one word
for it, yes.
Discovering the betrayal
was one thing;
discovering that she
was far more perceptive
than I realized
was quite another.
She predicted my struggles
with addiction.
She saw it coming; I did not.
Is that what this is all about?
The fact that she...
she got one thing right?
It was, as you will recall
from the piece,
one of several quite
alarming prognostications
she made regarding my future.
One of several methods
by which I might self-destruct.
And if she was right
about one...
well...
We got a city in panic.
We got seven dead bodies
in the morgue.
Now, I know my guys are
everything they can
to find Howard Ennis.
And you're
the so-called
Howard Ennis expert.
You don't seem to have
the first clue
what he's up to next.
I admit,
Howard Ennis's behavior
up to this point
has been perplexing.
It contradicts
everything I've come
to know about the man.
Maybe the chaos is the point.
The randomness,
the deliberate
flouting
of his profile.
Maybe he wants to confuse you.
Ms. Watson has
a point, Captain.
Yesterday, I posited that Ennis
was attempting
to send us a message.
Today, I would posit that
the confusion is the message.
Captain, it's Ennis.
He just called
the station, asked
to speak to the person in
charge of the task force.
I got him on hold
in your office.
This is Captain Gregson
of the NYPD.
Hello, Captain Gregson
This is Howard Ennis.
May I assume that my old friend
Ms. Drummond is listening in?
Say your piece, Mr. Ennis.
I'll take that as a yes.
I saw you on the news
yesterday, Kathryn.
You are not aging well.
I'm calling because I thought
it was time
that I explained what I'm up to.
Actually, Mr. Ennis,
that won't be necessary.
Excuse me?
Well, I just figured it out.
This is entirely
about Ms. Drummond, correct?
You despise her.
Why? Well, obvious answer
is that she's the agent
most responsible
for your capture,
but I think there's more
to it than that.
You detest her because she...
solved you.
She climbed inside your head,
she pulled all
your ugly secrets out
and exposed them.
She demystified you.
And now you're doing everything
in your power to...
violate her profile of you,
rail against it,
show everyone that, well,
you never really were solved.
I like you.
I know who you are.
The Deductionist.
Accent gave you away.
You see, I did a lot
of reading in prison.
I, uh, found everything
Kathryn ever wrote.
And, by the way, you're right.
I do want to humiliate Kathryn.
But not because
of what she did to me.
Because of what she did
to my family.
Family? Are you
serious, Howard?
Didn't you just abandon your
dying sister in a hospital?
My father was a good man.
Wasn't his fault
that I ended up the way I did.
But you, Kathryn...
you alleged that he abused me
on a regular basis,
that he made me into the man
that I am today.
You know as
well as I know
that there were multiple
allegations of abuse.
My father, as most
of you probably know,
hung himself in his garage a few
months after the book came out.
My mother never really
got over it.
She died less than a year later.
If you ask me, Kathryn,
you all but put a gun
to their heads.
You want me to stop doing
what I'm doing,
Captain Gregson of the NYPD?
All you have
to do...
is give me Kathryn Drummond.
I think his demands
are quite reasonable.
A wall of newspaper clippings.
Journals filled
with his innermost inanities.
Souvenirs from the women
he murdered.
Ennis seems resolved
to leave no cliché unturned.
So we're no closer to finding
him than we were an hour ago.
I'm not so sure about that.
Standing inside
this space is like standing
inside Howard Ennis's brain.
It's hard to imagine there isn't
something of value here.
Actually, it's quite easy
to imagine.
He let us find
this place.
He left his cell phone here
so we could
triangulate its signal.
Why? 'Cause he's making a point.
This room represents who he was,
not who he is.
If there was anything
of value here,
Ennis never would
have led us to it.
Were you not listening
when I explained his plan
to become profile-proof?
Just out of curiosity,
how accurate were
your allegations
against the Ennis family?
The first allegations of sexual
abuse came in your profile,
but that was just
pure speculation.
Your book, on
the other hand,
you quoted an anonymous
source, a neighbor who claimed
that Ennis had confided
in him about the abuses.
So? What are you saying?
Well, I'm saying that you've
been known to cut corners.
In the article you wrote
about me, for example,
you included things that I
had said to you privately
as though they were
quotes for attribution.
You did say them, though.
And my article was right
about you.
So far.
So, was there a neighbor?
Or were you just guessing about
Ennis being sexually abused?
Ennis's pathology was consistent
with sexual abuse.
I've chased men like him
for 20 years.
It's been present
every single time.
Doesn't mean
it was present here.
So, if you were wrong,
it was a costly mistake.
Ennis's father quoted your
book in his suicide note.
You spurred Howard to
eight murders and counting.
Oh, like Howard Ennis needs
a reason to kill people.
Maybe he doesn't, but he
didn't have this reason
until you came along.
I'm going to bed.
You need anything?
I know that Kathryn Drummond
is obsessed with her work.
She prides herself on the...
accuracy of her profiles.
But to think she would've gone
so far as to destroy a family
to lend credence
to one of her claims.
Did you ever consider
the possibility
that she lied about you
in the article?
What would she have to gain?
I was never revealed as
the subject in the article.
No one ever compared me
to it.
Anyway, she got
a good deal right.
She predicted your drug problem.
So what?
You got clean.
You picked up
your career
right where you left off.
And you even made a friend,
something that Kathryn
claimed in her article
was virtually
impossible.
Me.
I'm talking about me.
Look, my point
is that...
the only thing
that anyone can predict
about people with 100% certainty
is that they'll change.
And anyone
who thinks otherwise
is kidding themselves.
Oh, my God. Is that...
You have a lovely
home, Watson.
Excellent light.
I found today quite taxing.
I thought your pornography
might distract me.
It's not my pornography.
The sex, I'm sorry to say,
is quite mundane.
And even if it wasn't,
the continuity gaffes
make it virtually
unwatchable.
What are you talking about?
Note the clock.
11:20 here.
1:00 there.
11:20 again. And many others.
If I were you, I wouldn't
be upset that a dirty movie
was produced in my home;
I would be upset
that it was produced
so sloppily.
And if you haven't already,
I strongly recommend
that you find yourself
a new spatula.
Watson!
Morning.
What is it?
Captain Gregson just texted,
said there was some sort
of disturbance at Patricia
Ennis's home last night.
It's possible that Howard
Ennis tried to break in.
If he did, he may
have left some clue
as to his whereabouts.
I'm in a hurry. Shall I select
your undergarments as well?
False alarm.
Ennis wasn't
here last night.
Well, someone was.
Couple of Miss Ennis's neighbors
threw these from the street.
I guess they didn't know about
her connection to her brother
until all the news coverage
this week.
Excuse me.
Yes, Chief.
Shall I take a picture
for Kathryn,
show her how her
little tome
affects the Ennis family
to this very day?
Hungry, Watson?
No, it's just this food.
It's exactly the opposite
of what someone
with kidney problems
should be eating.
The chips and the jerky
are high in sodium.
The licorice contains
glycyrrhizin,
which can interfere
with renal function.
She would've known
not to buy these.
What is it?
It's frankincense.
With a hint of carrot seed.
Yeah.
Essential oils,
concentrated liquids
that contain volatile aroma
compounds from plants.
I know what
essential oils are.
Typically, they're used
in aromatherapy.
But you can smell them
on the bottom
of her drinking glass?
Mmm.
Obviously you know
that liquids of this type
are highly toxic when ingested.
Especially
to the renal system.
Those things I said
about your parents...
I believed them when I put them
in your brother's profile.
But when I was
writing the book,
I couldn't prove the abuse.
I didn't want to back down,
so I made up a source.
After your family sued,
I paid one of your neighbors
to say he was the person
I talked to.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for
your father.
Your mother.
You.
I even owe
your brother an apology.
Come a little closer.
It's getting hard
for me to talk.
Sure.
Hey.
Captain said
you accompanied Agent Drummond
to speak with Miss Ennis.
Are you with them now?
Well, I'm in the hall.
Miss Ennis said
she wanted some water.
She destroyed her kidneys
deliberately.
She's working with her brother.
You can arrest me now.
It's done.
She came here
to apologize.
As though a simple "I'm sorry"
could make up for any of it.
You're referring
to the allegations she made
about your parents in her book.
I hate that word.
"Allegations."
Call them what they are.
Lies.
Finding out
what Howard did
devastated us.
But Kathryn Drummond's book
is what destroyed us.
All of your correspondence
over the last year
with your brother was monitored.
I imagine he procured
a cell phone from somewhere.
Yeah, he called me a little...
a little over a year ago
on the anniversary
of our dad's death.
He was crying.
He knew
that I was having a hard time.
Is that when he told you
to poison yourself?
I don't know
when he came up with the plan.
I... I-I just know that
it-it just sounded... right,
like it was...
it was supposed to happen.
He would be out there,
humiliating her,
and... I would be in here,
waiting for her.
I spoke to the surgeon
who was operating on her.
He thinks there's a chance
she'll survive.
And as for you--
you're going to jail.
Your kidneys are ruined,
and I'd say
you dropped a notch or two
on the old transplant list.
If I die, I die.
At least I know I died trying
to right a terrible wrong.
He targeted her
'cause he knew
that she was weak.
He knows that he could
bend her to his will.
Captain?
Ennis again.
They just transferred
him from the office.
This is Captain Gregson.
If your men are scrambling
to trace this call,
you can tell them to relax.
I'm calling through a router
that I placed across town
the other day.
'Course you are.
I heard on the news
that Kathryn's still alive.
I wanted you to know
that I think that's a shame.
Means I'm going to have
to keep making my point.
Sit tight.
What's up?
...S-O-P, Columbia University...
Signal for that station's
weak here.
So?
I need to look into something.
I'll call you shortly.
Mr. Ennis, do come in.
You could run,
but I-I do have your handgun.
It's just me. Please.
How'd you find me?
You were tuning your radio...
...when you called
Captain Gregson.
You dialed past a number of
frequencies, but two stood out.
Columbia University's station
has quite a weak signal
strength-- just a few miles--
but it dwarfs the Greek-language
station that you skipped past.
That's a micro-broadcaster,
a tiny little station for
the Greek immigrant community.
Now, very little overlap
between those two stations.
Just a few blocks, actually.
There are a number of empty
buildings within those blocks,
but most of those are homes
that are being remodeled.
This one was seized under
federal asset forfeiture laws,
and, um... ta-da!
So, what do you want?
You and I have both been
profiled by Kathryn Drummond.
You've read "The Deductionist."
You'll recall
she doesn't predict
a very pleasant end for me.
No, no, she doesn't.
She said that you were, um...
destined for self-destruction.
Mmm. The term she used
was self-annihilation.
"A tangle of incandescent talent
and ingrained character flaws
"that can only lead to one end:
self-annihilation."
I think Drummond's good.
Mmm.
She predicted my struggles
with addiction.
And in my less hopeful moments,
I wonder whether she might
be right about my ultimate fate.
She really has a way of getting
in your head, doesn't she?
Do you want to talk
about what she wrote?
No.
I'm not interested
in your words, Howard.
I'm interested in your actions.
I want to see
if either of us could be more
than our profile.
Her assessment of you is...
equally withering.
She believes that you are,
at your core,
a coward.
That regardless of the violence
of your assaults,
you would shrink away
from any confrontation
on equal terms.
So you come here alone
and lay out a gun
and a pair of handcuffs.
Precisely.
An experiment.
Two choices.
Now, if you are, in fact,
a chicken-heart,
you will choose the handcuffs
and surrender,
but if you're willing to face
an opponent face-to-face,
you'll choose the gun.
Personally,
I hope you go for the gun.
If you do,
it'll prove that Drummond
was wrong about you,
and if she was wrong
about you being a coward...
Then maybe she's wrong
about how you'll end up, too.
Maybe you won't die
after turning back to drugs
to dull those senses
that just won't quite shut down.
Is that what
you're terrified of?
That and clowns.
Word of warning.
If you reach for the gun,
I will reach for you.
The choice is yours.
Well done.
Technically only supposed
to strike you in the pate.
But I suppose rules
were made to be broken.
Well, before you punch me
or suspend me,
please keep in mind
that I texted you
the moment I heard Ennis
enter the building.
And the reason you decided
to engage him on your own?
I-I needed to learn something.
And did you?
I can't say, really.
I won't know for years.
Damn it!
Hey, Joan.
Radiator's acting up again?
Never know when Old
Faithful's gonna blow.
Listen, I appreciate
your calling ahead,
but we don't need to be
so formal about this.
It's a funny thing
about that radiator.
In the movie
that Cooper shot, uh,
he did several takes.
In some of the takes,
there's tape wrapped
around the air valve.
In others, there isn't.
It's a basic
continuity error.
I mean, I don't think
Cooper's directing career
is going to go anywhere.
Okay.
But it's almost as if
it started whistling,
and then they called
someone in to fix it.
Someone with
a special shortcut
involving electrical tape.
You were here the whole time,
weren't you, Bruce?
But at-at first,
I-I could not figure out
why you would do
something like that.
And then I remembered that
this place is rent-controlled,
so if I violate my lease,
you can evict me,
and then you can charge
market-value for this place.
I'm hardly the only guy,
with electrical tape.
No, but you know the actors
in that movie they work a lot
and there not hard to track down.
They all confirmed that you
were here the whole time.
You participated in the filming
of an unlicensed production.
That is against the law.
What do you want?
I want you and Cooper
to pay for all of my stuff
to be put in storage until
I find a new place.
I also want 1200 dollars
for that couch.
Because after everything
it's been through in that movie,
it needs to be
taken out back and shot.
How's Kathryn?
Unconscious, yet still
somehow annoying to me.
The doctor says she should
be out and about
practicing her pseudo
science in no time.
Oh, uh, I got you something.
To replace the one
desecrated by a sex act.
Thanks.
It gets better.
I don't understand. Nobody did
anything to my toothbrush
in that movie.
Not in the movie no,
certainly not.
I'm confused, are you saying that
you did something to my toothbrush?
Sherlock?
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player
www.tvsubtitles.net