Both victims work
for ZBZ Security.
Company has a contract
with the Turtle Bay Historical
Society right next door.
Now, nothing's missing
from the museum.
We're canvassing
the area
for the gun, shooter,
any possible witnesses.
So, thoughts?
Holmes?
Thoughts?
Sorry, sorry.
I was waiting
for Miss Watson.
I'm training her to analyze
every environment
with the keen eye
of the true detective.
Watson, thoughts?
Um, um...
Looks like both men have been
shot in the chest one time.
Judging from the scuff marks
on the concrete,
looks like they chased
the suspect up here,
who then fired twice
and then ran.
It's tough to say where he went.
The reason it's difficult
to say where he ran
is that no one ran
anywhere at all.
Here we have
two deceased gentlemen,
both of them wearing
the uniform of ZBZ.
Or so it would appear.
This man's patches were
recently sewn on,
and his clothes are
store-bought,
not made by
a uniform company.
So he was posing as a guard.
Nothing is missing
from the museum,
so we assume that he was looking
for access to the parking lot.
It's easy to rifle
through the cars
if you look like you work
for the security firm.
Now, what was in
his pockets? Pockets?
Pockets.
Yeah, see, you thought
he was a victim,
so you were looking
for identification.
But here we have
one, two, three, four
car registration cards.
Each one has
the owner's address on it.
See the game?
Pick an expensive car,
then you call an associate,
who burgles the home
of its owner while they're out.
This man is
a real security guard.
He saw this fellow
lurking around, followed him.
Bad man shoots good man.
Good man, while still alive,
wrests control of gun
from bad man, fires one shot.
Here we are.
One more thing.
His cell phone.
You're gonna check
the last number he dialed;
that's his partner.
He's probably robbing
a place right now.
Would you like to talk
to the burglar?
According to this,
his name is Loco Maurice.
You mustn't allow your failure
to discourage you.
(sighs) Didn't fail.
Not discouraged.
You didn't solve the case,
but you did notice
the incongruity
of the scuff marks.
The next step is learning
to extrapolate your way
to the truth.
Detection is not just
a skill, Watson.
It's a point of view.
You must train yourself
to be alert
to the bizarre,
the unusual,
that which has no place
in any given picture.
Like that stretch limo
with the driver staring
straight at us?
MAN:
Sherlock Holmes?
My name's Crabtree.
We got your name from
a Mr. Musgrave in London.
Local police told us
we'd find you here.
Oh. You say "we."
All I see is a you.
I'm a driver and attaché
for Mr. Gerald Lydon
of Lydon Industries.
You know the company?
You make everything
from Scotch Tape
to diamond-tipped drill bits.
Well, we have all the tape
and drill bits that we need.
Thank you very much.
Mr. Lydon has a proposal
for you.
I sit before you a lucid man.
Vital, I might say.
I hold 18 patents
and I can do 11 pull-ups
at age 58.
And I own exactly
16 forks.
I'm not entirely sure
what we're supposed
to be comparing.
Well, the point, Mr. Holmes,
is that in my good moments,
I'm every bit
the man I was.
But there are fewer
and fewer of those
because I have dementia.
And it's getting worse,
which is why Ms. Tompkins
is following me around.
You have my
condolences.
I don't want your condolences.
I want your help.
Have you ever heard
of hereditary cerebral
amyloid angiopathy?
Hereditary CAA.
It's a genetic disorder.
Less than 20,000
cases recorded.
Dementia is one
of the early symptoms.
And death is the final symptom.
And when it comes to me,
it will complete my murder,
because somebody did this to me,
and I need you to find out who.
So, it's a hereditary disorder.
You have to be born with it.
And there's no history
of it in my family.
They can do a lot of things
in labs now, you know.
And I've consulted with
some of the top geneticists,
and they tell me
that it's possible
that somebody gave me
this disease,
because they want me
out of power!
With all due respect,
maybe these
geneticists are right.
"Possible" does
not mean "likely".
It just means it's
not impossible.
That's what my family says,
that's what the police say,
that I'm paranoid,
that I'm delusional.
I hate to say this, but those
are also symptoms of CAA.
Look, they tell me
that you're the best.
Mr. Holmes, what will it cost
to buy you over to my side?
I only take cases when I believe
I'm acting in good faith.
Now, since I think that
naturally occurring dementia
is by far and away
the most likely explanation
for your plight,
I would not be doing that.
Would you pull over,
please, Crabtree?
I really am
truly sorry.
And I wish you
the best of luck.
(sizzling)
I read the last
stack of books.
No questions... asked.
But, uh, Jeremy Bentham is
a utilitarian philosopher.
That has nothing to do
with being a detective.
Bentham is the father
of modern criminology.
He said that crime is
the result of free will.
(doorbell rings)
Uh, you're gonna put
the acid away
before we answer the door,
right?
Delivery for you,
Mr. Holmes.
Thank you, Crabtree,
but I'm afraid I...
Oh, my God.
Is that...?
A bee in a box?
Yes, it is.
Fairly unimpressive
as far as bribes go.
Not if you're
an apiculturist.
That's an osmia avoseta--
solitary bee
famed for building exquisite
nests from flower petals.
It's on the verge
of extinction.
Crabtree, this is exquisite.
I cannot accept it.
Please tell Mr. Lydon
not to contact me again.
I told him you are a man
of convictions.
Perhaps now
he'll believe me.
This is ridiculous.
Single stick is your hobby.
It's not gonna help me
solve crimes.
(phone ringing)
Aim for the pate.
Good morning, Captain.
GREGSON: Are you in bed with
a guy named Gerald Lydon?
He tried to hire me.
I declined.
Well, that's not what he thinks.
You should get down here.
He's asking for you.
Why?
I don't know,
but we just arrested him.
He shot his driver--
guy named Crabtree.
He's being charged with murder.
♪ Elementary 1x17 ♪
Possibility Two
Original Air Date on February 21, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Lydon says
he can't remember.
His nurse witnessed
the whole thing, though.
There was some kind
of episode...
MAN: Yeah, well, I've
been patient. Excuse me.
I want to see my father!
No-- Hey, that's not
gonna happen, okay?
Your dad killed somebody.
This is a crime scene.
You guys got
to step back.
My father is sick.
Lydon's sons.
They're hands-on.
Anyway, he's asking
for you.
Says you're the only one
he'll see.
LYDON: Crabtree worked
for me for 23 years.
I know his partner; I helped
them adopt their daughter.
I don't know how I could
think that he would hurt me.
I'm-I'm having a hard time
holding on
to what's real
and what isn't.
Uh, this-this conviction
that someone did this to me...
...I don't know
where it comes from.
And maybe it is a delusion,
but everything in my life
feels so slippery,
except for that.
That feels solid.
Help me!
Hey, why do you have the box
with the bee in it?
We took Gerald
Lydon's case.
We did?
Well, frankly, I
couldn't say no to him.
It would have felt like denying
a dying man his last wish.
We are taking
this home,
and then we're going
to the genetics lab
which confirmed
his diagnosis.
At Watt Helix, we always say our
work isn't just about genetics.
It's about healthier food.
It's about a longer life.
It's about you.
Utter pabulum.
You'd think corporate science
would maintain
some vestige of dignity.
His portrait
was painted
by Kirian Boyd;
that's impressive.
This place is
a tower of ego.
So, you're Sherlock Holmes?
Hi.
And Joan
Watson, right?
Yes. Hi.
I'm Raph Keating;
I'm president here.
This is Natasha
Kademan.
She heads up the
medical research team.
'Tash, meet Holmes
and... Watson.
Hi.
Natasha Kademan. I know that name.
You wrote your dissertation
on "The Warrior Gene,"
did you not?
Ms. Kademan conducted
a study which many say
isolated the gene responsible
for sociopathic behavior.
Sterling work.
And why are you
plowing these fields?
My funding dried up.
The receptionist said you have
a question about Gerald Lydon.
Lydon thinks
someone gave him CAA?
Did you know
about this?
Sure. He used to talk
about it when he came in.
It sounded...
delusional.
And it may well be.
But Mr. Lydon insists
that geneticists,
whose names escape
him at the moment,
assure him that it is
technically possible.
You diagnosed
his condition,
your lab has researched
the disease extensively.
Is it?
I guess if you had
unlimited money, a great lab,
you probably could do it.
The CAA comes from a mutation
of the APP gene.
There may be seven people
out there
that might be able
to crack it.
Could I have their names
and addresses, please?
Seriously?
Mm-hmm.
(Holmes speaking Norwegian)
Hey, what's this?
You're a detective
now; you tell me.
Uh, it looks like
you left your dry cleaning
ticket for me.
Yes.
The reason being...
as well as being colleagues,
we are now embarking on a quite
unusual domestic partnership,
so we should aggregate our
errands, not duplicate them.
So, I get the dry cleaning
and you get what?
I shall clean our refrigerator
once monthly. Agreeable?
You should pick that up early.
We're leaving
for Norway tomorrow.
What?
I've been delving into
our "magnificent seven"
geneticists,
and I have discovered
a connection
which merits further
exploration.
This is Dr.
Ingvald Moller.
He runs a lab in Oslo,
which specializes in the study
of rare genetic
disorders.
(grunts)
He looks very...
Scandinavian.
He does.
Now, his lab is affiliated
with the National University,
which means it's publically
funded, and yet Dr. Moller
recently put a down payment on
a home on the Geiranger Fjord,
which was once owned by
the Norwegian royal family.
Lovely place.
Well outside what a public
servant could afford.
And interestingly,
his loan papers were cosigned
by one Carter Lydon.
Okay, so you think that Carter
paid this guy to figure out
how to give his father CAA.
Interesting.
But why do we have
to go to Norway?
Carter Lydon lives
right here.
I would rather question
a scientist
than a businessman.
And Norway has fjords
and glaciers,
and women reared on a diet
of wild-caught salmon.
Oh, that explains it.
(cell phone dings)
Looks like a molecule.
"The thing itself"--
that's a weird way to put it.
The warrior gene.
The warrior gene--
where's the dissertation?
This is Natasha Kademan's
monograph.
I seem to remember
something in the conclusion.
"When it comes to understanding
sociopathic behavior,
"understanding the warrior
gene is paramount.
It is the
thing itself."
So Natasha sent this.
She knows
what's going on.
Now she's panicking.
Now she's trying to
figure out her next move.
And if she's as smart
as she seems to be,
now she's realizing we
are her best option.
(cell phone dings)
Ms. Kademan?
Hello?
We found electrician's tape
covering the lock
on one of the back doors.
It looks like someone slipped in
to commit a burglary,
found Ms. Kademan
working late.
What were they trying
to burgle, blood samples?
No, I think not.
Ms. Kademan's murder
was connected
to the Gerald Lydon case.
The Gerald Lydon
case is closed.
I'm not talking about
the murder of his chauffeur.
I am talking about
the investigation into who gave
the man a substance
which induced his CAA.
Our most promising
suspect at the moment
is Lydon's son, Carter.
CAA is inherited; you can't
just give it to somebody.
Ms. Kademan thought
it was possible.
In fact, she thought
that's exactly what happened.
You believe her?
She made someone
nervous enough
to stab her
half a dozen times.
I'm inclined
to explore further.
this was no robbery.
That portrait...
was done by
Kirian Boyd.
It is by far the most
valuable object in here.
Oh, but it was
until it was stained
with several drops
of the killer's blood.
The victim's blood is
all over the place.
What makes you think that
came from the killer?
Excellent question.
Watson.
Uh, um...
Well, (sighs)
the spatters on the floor
indicate that she was
facing away from the portrait
when she was stabbed.
Um, all of her wounds are
on her anterior side,
so it's tough to see how her
blood ended up on the portrait.
Um, now if she tried
to fight back, then...
Then it's easy to see how
a blow to the killer's face
might result in
those stains.
Kudos, Watson.
Adequately done.
Oh, my God.
'Tash.
Who's that?
Victim's fiancé.
Came down for the I.D.
I knew that she was working
with a dementia patient
named Gerald Lydon,
but 'Tash never told me
that she thought
somebody dosed him.
I'm-I'm a geneticist, too,
so I'm pretty sure
she would've said something.
(sighs)
Honestly, I thought
you were gonna ask me
about that guy Benny.
Benny?
(groans) Cordaro?
Cordero?
He was in prison
for stabbing someone
when 'Tash was doing
her warrior gene research.
He claimed that she used his
blood without permission.
He came down here, like, a
month ago to scream at her.
Well, we'll look into it.
(woman singing in French
over speakers)
Oh, I haven't seen those
since organic chem.
Natasha thought you could
induce CAA.
You think that's how you do it?
Certainly seems possible.
But this--
Oh, don't touch.
Obviously, this is
a rendering of a molecule,
but the elements aren't labeled,
so I can't tell which molecule.
Until I do,
I can't say for certain.
Well, she did give you a list
of the best geneticists
in the world; have you thought
about asking one of them?
You mean our pool of suspects?
Hmm. If I haven't decoded
this thing by morning,
we'll send it to someone
unconnected with the case.
I worked hard on that dinosaur.
(sighing)
I spent some time with that
picture Natasha sent last night.
I figured out most of
the elements, and then the rest
I sent on to my old
genetics professor.
In the middle of the night?
Well, he has insomnia,
so he's always up
between 2:00 and 4:00 anyway.
You were romantically involved
with your genetics instructor.
Jerry was amazed by this.
He said it was like
looking at
something out of
Leonardo da Vinci's sketchbook.
It's a man-made chemical
from the polycyclic
hydrocarbon family.
It's like we thought.
This is a mutagen
that targets the
stretch of the genome
that is responsible
for hereditary CAA.
That's quite beautiful.
So,
all we have to do now is prove
that someone paid a genius
to develop this
and then used it
on Gerald Lydon.
That should be
a fascinating day's work.
It's cold.
Did you pick up my sweaters?
Seriously?
I will thank you
for the molecular formula
when I'm sufficiently warm
to do so.
(sighs)
(man speaking Polish
over television)
(doorbells jingle)
Hi.
(groans)
(speaking Polish)
She say, "Wait one second,
almost commercial."
(speaking Polish)
She say she never
seen you before.
Uh, I'm here
for a friend.
Wow, that's
quite a coat.
It's warm.
Um, don't you want money?
(speaking Polish)
She says $75.
For four sweaters?
Okay, $19 then.
Um, could I get a receipt?
No.
(doorbells jingle)
GREGSON:
So, Benny, you're saying
you were mad at Ms. Kademan.
Hell yeah, I
was mad at her.
I signed up for her study
to get brownie points
with the parole board.
She called me
an incurable sociopath.
You think that didn't
add time to my sentence?
So you went to Ms. Kademan's
office a few weeks ago
to threaten her, and last
night you killed her.
BENNY:
No.
GREGSON:
You don't have an alibi.
BENNY:
Yeah, but it wasn't like that.
What's with Main
Moon Dry Cleaning?
I'll admit the new management
is not much for efficiency,
but I find them charming.
(groans)
That's Benjamin Cordero.
Career blackmailer,
general blackguard.
Also innocent of the murder
of Natasha Kademan,
which I would very much like
to get back to solving.
BELL:
We don't need your DNA, genius.
You're a convicted felon.
We got a sample on file.
(cell phones ding)
GREGSON: Which means you got
a very short window
to cooperate with us.
(cell phones ding)
So, you want to make
a statement?
(banging on window)
You delay,
but time will not!
That's a quote--
Benjamin Franklin.
I know who said it.
I just don't know why you're
shouting it through the mirror!
This crime has
a certain elegance to it.
It involves careful planning,
scientific innovation,
a country home in
the Norwegian fjords.
That prosaic individual
has no place in it.
He had beef with
Natasha Kademan.
He's been to jail
for a stabbing.
Okay by you if
we run his DNA?
It's not my place
to tell you your job.
But by the time
you get your results back,
I will be that much closer
to proving that someone,
most probably Carter Lydon
working in concert
with a Norwegian geneticist,
poisoned Gerald Lydon with
a hitherto nonexistent compound
and then murdered
Natasha Kademan
when she found out
what they were up to.
Oh, I take it back.
Your version sounds
much more plausible.
Sorry, you think
there's actually something
to my dad's story?
We do.
And we think that elements
within the company
may be responsible.
Elements?
What elements?
I'd rather not say.
What I would like
is root access
to your company's servers.
We may be able to build a case
by tracking e-mails.
Uh, I mean, I don't know
if I can do that, guys.
I mean, there are big
changes coming here.
I don't even know what job
I'm gonna have next week.
Your job?
We're talking about your father.
CARTER:
My father doesn't
need your help.
That's for him
to determine.
Thanks for your text.
Mm-hmm.
And actually,
it's not my dad's decision.
He was declared legally
incompetent this morning.
Your services are
no longer needed.
Get out.
Actually, our contract
with your father calls
for termination in writing,
countersigned by both parties.
Sign here.
WATSON:
It worked.
The thing with
the termination letter.
I mean, obviously
we don't even have
a contract with Gerald Lydon,
but I noticed that Carter
bites his nails.
People who bite
their nails tend
to chew writing
implements as well.
Well, he never
asked for it back.
You know,
maybe we can get a DNA sample.
If he killed Natasha,
then we've got him.
I just need a plastic bag.
Not a bad gambit, Watson, though
a hair sample would be better.
A hair sample?
What do you want from me?
Nothing. I have
a sample already.
Carter, like many people
who slick their hair back,
carries a comb, so I
picked his pockets.
If you want to
be a detective,
you should get in the habit
of carrying evidence bags.
(cell phone ringing)
Detective Bell.
We may well have
cracked the case.
Benny Cordero's DNA
came back a match
for the blood at the scene.
I hate to burst your bubble,
but we're booking him
for murder.
That's not my blood.
No way, no how.
It's not even possible.
Look, we test 13 different
genetic markers.
Every single one of them
was a perfect match.
Then somebody set me up.
Look, I know
this looks bad.
Doesn't look like anything.
We know what happened.
It's over.
W-What if I did have
an alibi?
I live
in this courtyard building,
and the couple across the way,
they don't close
their blinds that much.
I notice stuff
with the husband
and the nanny.
Just holding hands first,
then some kissing.
So the night
the Kademan lady got killed,
I got my camera out,
I put the zoom lens on.
So you're saying your alibi
is that you were home,
taking blackmail shots
of one of your neighbors?
Well... yeah.
Are these the same sweaters
I picked up yesterday?
You're a detective
now; you tell me.
Yes, same sweaters.
You left them outside my room
by accident?
I was setting
up to practice
my calligraphy
at the same time
I was unpacking
the dry cleaning.
There was a mishap.
We agreed that you were in
charge of the dry cleaning,
but we didn't say how
often you'd have to go.
Fine, well,
I'm picking another place.
When they're
your clothes,
you're free to go
wherever you like.
My clothes have to
go to Main Moon.
I'm sensitive to the
chemicals in dry cleaning,
and they use only the
gentlest emollients.
Really?
Yes.
Now, as much as I
love dry cleaning,
I'm trying to get
some thinking done.
Oh, so you still think Benny
Cordero didn't kill Natasha?
Never mind the fact that
no one plans a blackmail
and commits murder
on the same evening,
the man has no connection
to the Lydons,
and his supposed victim
texted us the formula
for inducing CAA
and got stabbed
20 minutes later.
Can't be a coincidence.
I'm trying to think of
alternative explanations.
Possibility one
is obvious,
which is why Mr. Cordero
put it forth himself.
Someone got ahold
of his blood
and then planted it
at the crime scene.
Not unheard of,
but also an
investigative dead end.
I can't prove that
it didn't happen.
I get absolutely nowhere
looking into it.
There's no evidence that anyone
other than Benny Cordero
was at Watt Helix
that night,
which is why I'm considering
possibility two.
WATSON:
It's blank.
Possibility two has stubbornly
refused to reveal itself.
Well, keep staring
at the wall.
I'm sure it's hiding
in there somewhere.
(speaking Polish)
(doorbells jingle)
Hi again.
Little accident
with the sweaters.
Slow day yesterday?
(speaking Polish)
She say, "Why you ask that?"
So she understands English,
she just doesn't speak it?
I'm only asking because, uh,
that mink coat is
in the same exact place
it was yesterday,
so that means
that hasn't been turned on
since I left.
(speaking Polish)
She say, "Slow day yesterday."
Do dry cleaners
get robbed a lot?
I just noticed that you have
six very expensive
security cameras here
and then two more
at the front door.
Seems like a lot.
They came when we buy place.
Problem?
No, that's not...
That's not a problem.
Thanks.
(doorbells jingle)
I figured it out.
I-I'm sorry to interrupt,
um, but I know exactly
what you were up to.
I sincerely doubt that.
Would you excuse us
for a moment?
There is a reason why you keep
sending me to Main Moon.
They don't do any business,
they don't even know
how much to charge, and they
have a load of security cameras.
There's definitely
something going on.
Watson, I admire
your enthusiasm.
I have no idea
what you're on about.
You wanted me to notice.
I wanted my sweaters.
Now, I know I have counseled you
to be alert,
but that doesn't mean that
there is a conspiracy lurking
behind every door.
Okay, so what are
you up to then?
After you went to bed,
I spent a good hour
trying to reckon
how an innocent man's blood
could wind up at the scene
of a murder
if it wasn't planted there.
Then I remembered
something that you said.
The late Mrs. Kademan
gave us a list
of the top geneticists
in the world.
Why not ask them?
Everyone, say hello
to Miss Watson.
ALL:
Hi.
Good morning.
I left Dr. Moller from Norway
off the list.
Now, the others were
a bit confused at first,
but after I posed
the problem to them,
we had quite
a lively discussion, didn't we?
Yes.
Turns out,
there is another possibility.
Jurgi, would you please explain
your breakthrough
to Miss Watson?
It's quite simple, really,
though I should give you
a grounding
in cellular biology.
Another time perhaps, Jurgi.
Actually, you know what,
I'll call you all back.
Thank you.
He's a brilliant man,
little bit long-winded.
Gist of it is: law enforcement
runs a standard DNA test
called STR analysis.
It's actually a
bit imprecise.
It tests 13 loci
against each other,
when there are
countless possibilities.
All assembled agree
that technology has advanced
to the point
where you could manufacture
a match of 13 loci.
So you're saying you can fake
a DNA sample?
All you would need is access
to a top-tier lab
and access
to someone's genetic code.
And I'm not just saying
that you could do it,
I just regathered my
round table to tell them
that in this case,
someone did do it.
How could you
possibly know that?
I called in a favor
from the medical examiner's
DNA lab.
They provided a sample
of the blood found
at the scene of Natasha
Kademan's murder
for a full workup.
A friend of Jurgi's at
Columbia handled the analysis.
All 13 loci tested
in STR analysis
were a perfect match
for Benny Cordero,
but there were no other
loci at all in the sample.
So you're saying someone
stripped a blood sample
of its genetic material
and then created a match
for the loci
they knew the police
would check?
Only a geneticist would be able
to carry that out.
It seems like everyone connected
to this case is a geneticist.
But only one pointed us
in the direction
of Benny Cordero
in the first place.
GREGSON: So, this
morning, my consultant
marches into my office
and says the damndest thing.
He thinks it's possible
to manufacture a DNA sample.
Thing is, he
was right.
The blood that we found
at the scene
of your fiancée's murder,
it didn't belong
to Benny Cordero.
It was just designed
to look that way.
Well, that sounds kind of crazy.
Now, you work for
Ubient Pharmaceuticals, right?
I bet they have nice labs.
What are you saying?
Paul, come on.
We know the sample was faked.
We know you pointed us at Benny
Cordero in the first place.
We know you had access to his
genetic makeup via your fiancée.
We know your employer
has probably the top
lab in the city.
We also have a
pretty good idea
of the equipment you'd
need to manufacture
a fake DNA sample.
Now, we can get a court
order to look at it,
but as it turns out,
we don't need to.
We shared everything
we know with your bosses.
They gave us access.
Our crime scene unit is
processing the lab as we speak.
You may think you've
covered your tracks,
but if you made the sample
there, we' find it.
Why did you murder your fiancée?
(chuckles)
Right after we got engaged,
'Tash and I had complete
genetic workups done.
Natasha asked them to check
us both for the warrior gene,
the gene that she isolated
in her research--
just being thorough.
Turns out, I have it.
My DNA says I'm a sociopath.
She said it wouldn't
change anything, but...
I could feel her pulling away.
Then the late-night
phone calls started,
the long hours at work.
She was moving on.
Moving on and stepping out.
You think she was
cheating on you?
A guy knows.
And I even had a name.
Lincoln Dunwoody.
I knew that she was planning
to leave,
and she doesn't get
to make that call.
So you're saying you
murdered her out of jealousy?
I guess I knew for a while
that it was gonna end like this.
That's why I made the blood.
But last Tuesday,
she called to cancel
our dinner date
on my birthday.
That was it.
So where does
Carter Lydon fit in?
The formula for inducing
hereditary CAA?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm talking about the plan
to poison Gerald Lydon.
(sighs)
Look, I killed 'Tash.
Okay? I am telling you that.
But I don't know
how to induce CAA.
I don't even remember
what it stands for.
(phones ringing,
people talking quietly)
Hey.
I caught most of the Reeves
stuff from the bullpen,
then Bell filled me in
on the rest.
Look, I know you thought
it was all connected
and that finding Natasha's
killer was gonna help explain
what happened to
Gerald Lydon,
but it didn't work
out that way.
But we do have a
murderer in custody,
and you got around
a fake DNA sample.
Strange name.
Did you know there's no one
called Lincoln Dunwoody
in the whole of New York?
At first, I thought
Natasha Kademan's
paramour was using
a fake name for their affair.
But...
...when you separate
the two names,
treat them as two surnames
rather than
one nonexistent person, you get
a very interesting result.
This Lincoln family
has a long history
of generous philanthropy.
So, too, does
this Dunwoody family.
The Lincoln family's
patriarch is James Lincoln.
He recently retired
after a sudden
and unexpected diagnosis
of cerebral amyloid angiopathy.
There's no history of
the disease in his family.
Hmm.
That is weird.
I don't think Natasha Kademan
was having an affair at all.
I think she was trying to expose
a plot to poison these men.
Well, you only know
of two cases, right?
I mean, CAA is
incredibly rare,
but that could be
just a coincidence.
What if there was
a third person stricken?
Is there?
I don't know.
But I do know that
a woman called Greta Dunwoody
recently retired as president
of her family's foundation.
She's dropped off
the society pages,
and no one is quite sure
what's happened to her.
Well, we need
to find her.
Apparently, the family's
keeping shtum.
But read the list of grants.
Well, they just donated $20
million to St. Bede's Hospital.
If she was sick, I would say
that would be a good place
to start looking.
(piano playing classical music)
Ms. Dunwoody?
(music stops)
They told us
we'd find you in here.
Um... these are for you.
They're beautiful.
Thank you.
You're not my son, are you?
No, we...
we just thought we'd
check in on you.
Oh, that's nice.
Do you mind if I practice?
I have to keep practicing
if I want to get into Juilliard.
(plays out of tune chord)
(playing classical music)
Amazing.
The brain decays, but
muscle memory remains.
Gerald Lydon wasn't
the only target.
Someone's poisoning
these people.
WATSON: You're cleaning
the fridge out now?
It's my half of our agreement.
Well, I was hoping
you could help me figure out
who's giving
rich people CAA.
Yes, that was
first on my list.
Now the refrigerator.
You have a suspect. Who?
You're a detective;
you tell me.
(sighs)
Fine.
Uh...
Okay, it's not Carter Lydon.
I mean, he has a motive
to want his father sick,
but he has no reason
to attack strangers.
Maybe he cosigned that loan
for that guy in Norway
because he wanted him
to help with
his father's case.
So who does have
motive to attack
three seemingly
unconnected strangers?
The victims are
three rich people.
They all have
charitable foundations.
The only people
that would benefit
from wealthy philanthropists
coming down with CAA
are the people raising money
to study the disease.
Induce CAA in some of
New York's wealthiest,
then sit back and wait
for donations to flow in.
Not all the victims
would contribute,
so you'd have
to dose more than one.
Did you know
the Lincoln Foundation
gave a rather generous grant
to the research labs
at Watt Helix?
Natasha's company.
She was a whistle-blower.
There's got to be,
what, 50 people
working in research there?
But how many of them
are capable of inventing
an entirely new molecule
which attacks a specific gene?
Well, it's got to be
the smartest person there.
Of course,
that person might not still
work there on a daily basis.
GREGSON:
Mr. Watt,
did you know that before
Ms. Kademan was killed,
she was working to
expose a scandal?
It's quite a story.
She thought that
someone at Watt Helix
was inducing mutations
in wealthy people
to attract funding
for research into CAA.
We think she was right.
That's... shocking.
I assume
you have evidence.
Whoever developed
the molecule was brilliant.
A towering intellect.
Someone a lot like you.
I hope that's not
an accusation.
Brian Watt is
a decorated physician.
He has a sterling
reputation.
Why would he risk that for...
whatever you're describing?
We spent a good deal of time
puzzling over that ourselves,
didn't we? Yeah.
We came up with a theory,
but we couldn't be
sure of it until we got
a good look at you.
You have hereditary CAA,
don't you, Mr. Watt?
That's why you're semi-retired,
and that's why
you haven't said a word
since you came in.
We know it's in your family.
Probably why you got into
genetics in the first place,
find a way around
the death sentence
that you carry in your DNA.
But you got sick.
Research wasn't
going fast enough.
So in your more lucid moments,
you hatch a plan to attract
bigger and bigger money.
All you'd
have to do
is to introduce the chemical
you developed
into someone's I.V.
All the victims had procedures
at Stuyvesant Memorial,
a hospital where you still
hold privileges.
You're wrong.
Well, then, you won't mind
if we take a look
inside your home, will you?
'Cause there won't be
any more of the chemical
needed for
further attacks.
We have team of detectives
heading to his home
as we speak.
REPORTER:
A stunning arrest today,
as entrepreneur Dr. Brian Watt
has been charged in a bizarre
string of poisonings...
Hi there.
Are my sweaters ready?
I didn't think so.
This is Detective Bell
from the NYPD.
I told him about
the world's worst dry cleaner's,
and he got curious.
BELL:
Do you know who bought
this place from
the Korean couple
who used to own it?
It's a shell company.
I can't even pronounce it,
but my friends at the NYPD
know all about it.
They think it's
linked to smuggling,
human trafficking...
other fun stuff.
So now I know why you're
so terrible at dry cleaning.
Because the only thing
your owners want you to clean
is their money.
BELL: And given all the security
cameras you have in here,
I bet if we execute this search
warrant we brought with us,
we'd find plenty of it.
Is that true?
(speaking Polish)
All right, get up.
Put your hands behind your back.
♪ Everything
♪ Is crystal clear...
I did it!
Close that door immediately!
What's up?
I was examining
the osmia avoseta
that Gerald Lydon gave me,
and it got loose.
Oh, so there's an almost-extinct
bee flying around in here?
Yes, and I would rather
it didn't get out.
Okay. Well, I
took care of it.
That dry cleaner
you sent me to,
you deduced what
they were up to.
Bell sent in somebody to search
it, and everybody's arrested.
Thought I was gonna
have to send you back there
three times more times.
Well done.
Why didn't you tell me
when I came to you yesterday?
I wanted you to...
learn to trust
your own instincts.
♪ When the world
stops making sense... ♪
Good detective knows that
every task, every interaction,
no matter how seemingly banal,
has the potential
to contain multitudes.
I live my life alert
to this possibility.
I expect my colleagues
to do the same.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
www.tvsubtitles.net